翻译      土它   Clara   ether   fevolrits
校对      Clara
德语翻译+时间轴      西柚
特效      何故授衣
间谍之桥
冷战高潮期间
美国和苏联政府互相忌惮
对方的核能力以及核目的
双方都派遣了间谍
同时也追捕对方的间谍
改编自真实事件
布鲁克林
白沙瓦空军基地 巴基斯坦
十天证词之后 阿贝尔间谍案将交予陪审团
间谍的命运掌握于陪审团手中
公正时刻 间谍案交予陪审团
自毁
沃特斯 考恩 及多诺万事务所
德国 柏林
东柏林
柏林
格林尼克桥
加里•鲍尔斯与1977年死于一场直升机事故  当时他任职于KNBC新闻
死后 他于2000年被授予了中情局局长奖章
以及美国空军战俘奖章 还有2012年的银星奖
1962年 弗雷德里克•L•普莱尔从耶鲁大学获得了 他的经济学博士学位
他现在是索思摩学院的经济学名誉教授 及 高级研究学者
有了鲍尔斯-阿贝尔人质交换成功的先例
詹姆斯•多诺万应肯尼迪总统之邀 接手了更多代表美国政府的谈判
1962年的夏天 他被派去古巴 就释放猪湾事件1113名人质被俘事件
在多诺万的谈判之后 他一共拯救了9703名男人 妇女 和儿童
同菲德尔•卡斯特罗谈判
鲁道夫•阿贝尔回到了俄国之后
和妻女重聚 他的间谍身份始终不为苏联大众所知
下一站 宽街
The next stop is Broad Street.
下一站是宽街
Broad Street will be next.
上楼 这边
Upstairs. This way.
他没从这上来吗 发现什么了吗
He didn't come up this way?Anything?
他没上来 我们再下去
He's not up here.Go back down.
抱歉 抱歉
Excuse me.Excuse me.
继续开然后在转角处停车
Go ahead and park around the corner.
不速之客啊
Visitors.
不介意我把假牙拿一下吧
Do you mind if I fetch my teeth?
上校 请您转过身去 好吗
Colonel, would you turn around, please?
在床上坐下
Sit down on the bed.
过来
Let's go.
呃 它们 我的假牙在水池上
Uh, they're in the... The teeth are in the... On the sink.
看着我 我们是联邦调查局
Look at me. We are agents
的特工
from the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
看着我
Look at me!
我正跟你说话呢
I'm talking to you.
我们收到情报
We've received information
指出你参与了间谍活动
concerning your involvement in espionage.
你现在可以选择跟我们合作
You can either cooperate with us right now,
不然我们就逮捕你
or you'll be under arrest.
听懂了了吗 上校
Do you understand, Colonel?
并没有
No, not really.
为什么你一直叫我上校
Why do you keep calling me "Colonel"?
你得穿好衣服
You need to get dressed.
我们要搜查你的房间
We have to search your apartment.
你介意我整理一下调色盘吗
Would you mind if I, uh, cleaned my palette?
不然那些颜料就没用了
The paints, it'll get ruined otherwise.
就在你后面
It's just behind you there.
我这有块布
I have a cloth myself.
谢谢你
Thank you.
－好了 现在开始搜查 －谢谢你
-All right, start searching the place. -Thank you.
好 搜查床垫
All right, search the mattress,
床 地板 他的椅子
the bed, the floorboards, his chair.
你能把烟头放到窗台上的烟灰缸里吗
Would you put that in the ashtray on the windowsill there?
好好检查那个桌子
Take a good look at that desk.
看下这张桌子
Let's see the desk.
我不想毁掉这个
Wouldn't want to get this ruined.
不要说他是我的人
Don't say "my guy."
他不是我的人
He's not "my guy."
是的 他就是你的人 我们在说谁呢
Yes, he's "your guy." Who are we talking about?
我们在说的是一个在我的客户 保险公司投保了的人
We're talking about a guy who was insured by my client.
所以 不要把他说成是我的人
So, don't make him "my guy."
好吧
Okay, fine.
我要说的是 这个你的客户投保的人
My point is, the guy insured by your client,
他没有否认这些事情的发生
he doesn't deny that any of these things happened.
这些 这些事吗
"These... These things"?
是的 这五件事
Yes, these five things.
等等 打住 打住
Wait, hold it, hold it, hold it.
不是五件事
Not five things.
是一件事
One thing.
很明显 就是五件事
Clearly, it's five things.
不好意思 对我来说可不是
Well, I'm sorry, it's not clear to me.
有五件事吗 说给我听听
Five things? Explain it to me.
这是不言而喻的
It's self-evident.
好吧 那就跟我说说 用一种让我信服的方式
Okay, then tell me what happened.
来说说怎么会是五件事
Tell me the story in a way that makes sense for five things.
好 没问题 你的人
Fine, absolutely. Your guy is...
不是我的人 我的客户投保的人
Not my guy. Insured by my client.
你的客户投保的人
The guy insured by your client
在19号州际公路上开车时
is driving down State Highway 19
他的车子失控了 撞到了我的五个客户
when he loses control of his car and hits my five guys,
就是这五个人请我来代表他们
the five guys who hired me to represent them
因为你方不履行赔偿
because you're not honoring your claim.
你的意思是 我的客户 保险公司不赔吗
You mean my client is not honoring the claim, the insurance company?
多诺万先生 我们都清楚该谁赔
Mr. Donovan, we're all clear on who's who, here.
除了我的客户该赔的
Except my client honors every claim.
贝茨先生 他们已经承担了
They do, Mr. Bates.
每一件合法的赔偿
Every single legitimate claim,
在这个男人的保单中
their liability,
达到了赔付的上限
which is $100,000 per accident,
也就是每起事故10万美元
in the case of this man's policy.
这是一件赔偿案
And this is one claim.
根据你的说辞 他撞了你的五个客户
According to your description, "He hit my five guys."
我的客户投保的人 只发生了一起事故
The guy insured by my client had one accident.
一起 一起 一起
One, one, one.
车子失控 撞到了五名摩托车手
Losing control of the car and hitting five motorcyclists.
从我们的角度来看 就是五起事故
From their point of view, five things happened.
好吧 听着 鲍勃 噢 能叫你鲍勃吗
Well, look, Bob. May I? Bob?
我叫吉姆
"Jim."
如果我去打保龄球然后掷出一球 那是一件事
If I go bowling and I throw a strike, one thing happened.
不是十件事
Ten things didn't happen.
吉姆 我的客户可不是保龄球瓶
Jim, my guys aren't bowling pins,
不过你们可能就是把他们当成了保龄球瓶
as much as your guy may have treated them as such.
如果 让我说完 让我说完
If... Let me finish. Let me finish.
如果你的房子投了10万美金的保险
If your house is insured for $100,000
然后一个飓风卷走了它
and a tornado carries it away,
飓风卷走的是一整幢房子
it carried away one house.
而不是每件家具
It didn't pick up every stick of furniture
然后在不与摧毁房子同时的情况下 单独摧毁了家具
and destroy it in a separate incident.
按照你的说法
If that is what you're saying,
保险公司的赔偿就没有个限度了
well, then there is never any limit to our liability
那保险业就要垮了
and that is the end of the insurance business.
还有 鲍勃 没人是安全的了
And then, Bob, nobody is safe.
沃特斯 考恩 及多诺万事务所 我该把你的电话接到谁那
Watters, Cowan and Donovan. How may I direct your call?
多诺万先生 早上好
Morning, Mr. Donovan.
早上好 艾莉森
Good morning, Alison.
我把你和保诚公司上午九点的会面取消了 先生
I moved your 9:00 a.m. with Prudential, sir.
为什么
Why did you do that?
我让她这么做的
I asked her to.
没事吧 汤姆
Is everything all right, Tom?
你还是把你的东西交给艾莉森 然后和我到里面谈谈吧
Why don't you leave your stuff with Alison. Come on inside.
发生了件很重要的事情
Something pretty important has come up.
有人来这见我们
Somebody's here to see us.
纳塔莉正把你的咖啡端过来
Natalie's getting your coffee.
雀巢的 加奶 加两块糖 对吧
Nescafe, cream, two lumps, right?
正是 谢谢
That's right. Thanks.
－林恩 －吉姆
-Lynn! -Jim!
很高兴再次见你 你的家人还好吗
Nice to see you again. How's the family?
很好 谢谢  安妮好吗
Great, good. Thanks. How's Annie?
杀气腾腾啊 我们假期邀请了亲戚们
Homicidal. We had the in-laws for the holiday.
如果她因此暴走的话 至少她会有很好的辩护律师
Well, if she acts on it, she'll have good representation.
说吧 有什么事
Now, what's up?
好 事情是这样的
Okay, here's the thing.
那个捉到的苏联间谍 我们想让你替他辩护
The Soviet spy they caught, we want you to defend him.
这是起诉书
Here's the indictment.
哇哦
Wow.
我不知道我想不想接这单活
I'm not sure I wanna pick that up.
被告人不认识任何律师
The accused doesn't know any lawyers.
联邦法庭就把这案子扔给了我们
The federal court tossed it into our lap.
律师公会委员会进行了投票
The Bar Committee took a vote.
他们一致推选了你
You're the unanimous choice.
公众能否认为这个男人受到了公平待遇
It was important to us...
这对我们很重要 吉姆
It's important to our country, Jim,
这对我们国家也很重要
that this man is seen as getting a fair shake.
不然美国的司法体系会受到质疑
American justice will be on trial.
是 当然 照你这么说的话
Well, of course, when you put it that way,
被选中是我的荣誉
it's an honor to be asked.
但是 林恩 我是个代表保险公司的律师
But, Lynn, I'm an insurance lawyer.
很多年都没有碰过刑事案了
I haven't done criminal work in years.
就像是骑自行车 一旦会了就忘不了了 对吧
It's like riding a bike, isn't it?
你在纽伦堡可是数一数二的
You distinguished yourself at Nuremberg.
但那次我是在控方这边的
I was on the prosecution team.
这不打紧
Not the point.
你对刑事条款可不陌生
You're no stranger to criminal law.
吉姆 看看现在的情形
Jim, look at the situation.
这个间谍被公众唾骂
The man is publicly reviled.
那我也会被骂
And I will be, too.
是 是被些无知的民众骂
Yes, in more ignorant quarters.
但这就是为什么一定要给他请个辩护律师
But that's exactly why this has to be done,
还得请个知名律师
and capably done.
这件事看起来不能像是我们的司法体系
It can't look like our justice system
把人直接扔进灰烬里
tosses people on the ash heap.
假设我接了这单 控告他的证据是什么情况
Suppose I did, what's the evidence look like?
非常多
Pretty overwhelming.
好极了
Great. Great.
人人都会恨我 不过至少我会输掉官司
Everyone will hate me but at least I'll lose.
那么 你怎么看 汤姆
Well, what do you think, Tom?
我们事务所肯定会被牵连 我还在这工作呢
The firm will suffer. I have work here.
我觉得这是爱国者的义务
I think it's a patriotic duty.
这是个至关重要的任务
It's an important mission.
我跟林恩说了 事务所不能拒绝
I told Lynn, the firm can't say no,
你看起来也很难拒绝
and you'd have a tough time saying no, too.
我觉得你还是得为这个混蛋辩护
I think you have to defend the son of a bitch.
所以你同意了
So, you're doing it?
同意啥
Doing what?
帮阿贝尔辩护 就是那个苏联间谍
Defending Abel, the Soviet spy.
可能会 我还得和
I may. I have to speak to...
等等 你怎么知道的 他们在事务栏张贴了这件事吗
Wait, how do you know? Did they post it on the bulletin board?
没有 我跟理查德·厄尔聊了聊
No, I... I was talking to Richard Earl...
听着 如果我要做这件事 我会需要你的帮助
Look, if I do this, I'm going to need your help.
你今晚能上班吗
Can you work tonight?
这个 我晚餐有个约会 先生
Well, I have a dinner date, sir.
这是周二对吧 没事 我晚上没事 完全空闲
It's Tuesday, right? Yeah, no, I'm free, completely free.
先生 谢谢您
Thank you, sir.
但这也是一种荣誉
But it's also an honor.
律师公会邀请我
And the Bar Association asked me
因为他们想告诉公众 即使是一个间谍
because they want to show that even a spy
也能得到一个有名律师的辩护
gets a capable advocate.
只不过 我们不要这份荣誉也挺好
Well, maybe it's the kind of honor we could do without.
嘿 亲爱的 你在家做什么
Hey, honey, what are you doing home?
我被放鸽子了
I got stood up.
这太可恶了
Well, that's despicable.
是谁脑子进水了
Who is this knot-head?
我还是不说为好
I'd rather not say.
好吧 坐下吧 我们刚开始吃
Well, sit down. We just started.
人们都很害怕
People are scared.
他们都开始修建炸弹避难所 来保护自己
They're building bomb shelters to protect themselves
不受那种人的侵害
from people like this man.
我去商店的时候
I go to the store,
人们都在买罐装食物和补钾片
people are buying canned food and potassium tablets.
就是因为那个间谍和他代表的国家
It's all about this man and what he represents.
他是我们所有人的安全隐患 是个卖国贼
He's a threat to all of us. A traitor.
－谁是叛徒啊 －那些罗森堡人才是卖国贼
-Who's a traitor?  -The Rosenbergs were traitors.
那是谁
Who were they?
他们把原子弹的机密泄露给了俄国人
They gave atomic secrets to the Russians.
他们是美国人 他们背叛了自己的国家
They were Americans. They betrayed their country.
你不能说阿贝尔是个卖国贼
You can't accuse Abel of being a traitor.
他又不是美国人
He's not an American.
哦 听听你说的话
Oh, listen to yourself.
你现在就开始帮他辩护了
You're defending him already.
你已经在我这儿开始排练了
You're rehearsing it on me.
你说的你只是在考虑要不要接
You said you were just thinking about taking it.
我确实只是在考虑 只不过花了很大功夫
I am just thinking about it, just very hard.
每个人都应该有人去给他们辩护 每个人都很重要
Everyone deserves a defense. Every person matters.
吉姆 我们会得到什么
Jim, what do we deserve?
你知不知道那样别人会怎么看我们
Do you know how people will look at us?
一个要为卖国贼脱罪的律师的家人吗
The family of a man trying to free a traitor?
－他不是个卖国贼 玛丽 －好吧 好吧
-He's not a traitor, Mary. -Yes, yes.
罗格 接一下 他不是个卖国贼
Roger, get that! He's not a traitor...
为什么我什么事都得干
Why do I have to do all the work?
－直到我们说祷词你才能吃 －可我饿了
-Oh! You wait till we say grace. -I'm hungry!
他可算是这个国家最不受欢迎的人了
He's about the most unpopular man in this country,
现在你想当第二吗
and you're trying to take second place!
就是 然后我是第三
Yeah, and I'm third.
－卡罗尔 你只是跟一个坏人约会了而已 －我想吃了
-Carol,you just dated the wrong guy. -I wanna eat.
玛丽 我没想吵架的时候
Mary, don't make this an argument
别把这演变成一场争吵
when we're not having an argument.
你反对他 而我支持他吗
You're against him, I'm for him?
不 我不是支持他 我不会支持俄国派间谍过来
No, I'm not for him. I'm not for the Russians spying on us.
我是在维护他必须在法庭上有辩护律师的权利
I'm for his right to have a defense in a court of law,
这是因为法庭是讲法律的地方
which is why they call it a court of law.
我不是有意打断你们的晚餐的
I didn't mean to interrupt dinner.
一个讲法律的法庭 嘿 道格
A court of law... Hey, Doug.
才不是 道格 你好 吉姆刚刚动摇了
Oh, no, not at all. Hello, Doug. Jim was just flailing.
我没有 过来 道格 来和我们一起吃晚餐吧
I'm not flailing. Go ahead, Doug, you can join us for dinner.
我们今晚吃肉饼
We're having meatloaf tonight.
那么 你是过来帮吉姆
So, you came over to help Jim think about
考虑是不是要接这个案子的吗
whether he's taking the case?
哦不是 我们已经接了 这很令人激动 不是吗
Oh, we're taking it! It's exciting, isn't it?
神啊 我们感谢您
Lord, we thank thee for thy blessings
感谢您给予我们的恩赐
we are about to receive.
您以基督的名义对我们的恩赐 谢谢您 阿门
Thy bounty through Christ, our Lord. Amen.
早上好 先生 我是吉姆·多诺万
Good morning, sir. My name is Jim Donovan.
这是我的证书
These are my credentials.
我是沃特斯 考恩 多诺万事务所的合伙人
I am a partner in Watters, Cowan and Donovan.
我在1941年加入的纽约律师公会
I was admitted to the New York Bar in 1941.
你被3项19条公开罪名起诉
You have been charged with three counts and 19 overt acts.
意图密谋把美国国防
Conspiracy to transmit United States defense
和原子弹机密泄露给苏联
and atomic secrets to the Soviet Union,
密谋搜集机密
conspiracy to gather secrets,
以及没有作为外国探员注册
and failing to register as a foreign agent.
很多外国探员都注册了吗
Do many foreign agents register?
如果你不介意我这么问的话 先生
If you don't mind my asking, sir,
自从你被逮捕以来 你在哪呆着
since your arrest, where have you been?
我不能确定
I couldn't say for certain.
你不知道吗
You don't know?
他们把我载到一个机场
They drove me to an airport
押我上了飞机 押我下了飞机
and put me on a plane, took me off the plane.
来到了一个挺热的地方
Somewhere hot.
这挺热的
It's hot here.
更热 还很潮
Hotter, very humid.
他们把我关进一个房间
They put me in a room.
他们打你了吗
Were you beaten?
没有
No.
我跟他们谈了
I was talked to.
他们给我提供了条件
Offers were made.
这是什么意思
What do you mean?
他们同意雇佣我 为你们国家工作
Offers of employment, to work for your government.
我被告知 只要我合作
I was told if I cooperated,
他们就不会再对我提起诉讼
no further charges would be made against me.
还会给我钱
And I would be given money.
嗯
Hmm.
然后你拒绝了吗
And you declined?
如你所见
As you see.
好吧 当然我不可能去拥护你的所作所为
Well, of course I can't endorse that.
我觉得我有义务敦促你
I feel duty-bound to urge you
和美国政府合作
to cooperate with the U.S. government.
不过 我选择了拒绝
Well, I said no.
也许你可以帮我给你中情局的同事们转达一下 我是认真的
Perhaps you could relay to your friends at the CIA that I meant it.
不不不
No, no, no.
我不是调查机构的人
I... I don't work for the agency.
我不为政府工作
I don't work for the government.
我来这 是作为你的律师给你提供法律援助的
I am here to offer my services as your legal counsel.
如果你接受法律援助
If you accept them as such,
我就会为你工作
I work for you.
如果我接受你的帮助
If I accept you?
你是个厉害的律师吗
Are you good at what you do?
是啊 是 我相当棒
Yeah. Yeah, I'm pretty good.
那你代表过很多被起诉的间谍吗
Have you represented many accused spies?
没 还没
No, not yet.
这对我们来说都是第一次
This will be a first for the both of us.
是啊
Yes.
好的
All right.
好的 指的是你接受了
"All right"? You accept?
是的
Yes, all right.
好的
Good, okay.
那我们就现在开始
Let's start here.
如果你非常坚定地
If you are firm in your resolve
不和美国政府合作的话
not to cooperate with the U.S. government...
我是的
I am.
好的
Yeah.
那就不要和任何人谈起这件事
Then do not talk to anybody else about your case,
包括政府人员或者非政府人员
inside of government or out.
除了我以外 鉴于你应该无条件信任我
Except to me, to the extent that you trust me.
为你服务是我的任务 别人都没有这个义务
I have a mandate to serve you. Nobody else does.
讲实话 其他人都是盼着
Quite frankly, everybody else has an interest
把你送上电椅
in sending you to the electric chair.
好吧
All right.
你看起来一点都不惊慌啊
You don't seem alarmed.
那样有用么
Would it help?
我想要一些画材
I... I would like materials to draw with.
那不可能给你
That's not possible.
一支铅笔 一片纸
A pencil, a piece of paper.
香烟
Cigarettes.
求您了
Please?
多诺万先生 其实有像我一样的人
Mr. Donovan, you have men like me
在为你们的国家做着间谍
doing the same for your country.
如果他们被抓了
If they were caught,
我敢肯定 你会希望他们得到很好的对待
I'm sure that you would wish them to be treated well.
你叫什么
What's your name?
弗朗西斯·加里·鲍尔斯
Francis Gary Powers.
军衔 何处服役
Rank, service?
一等中尉 美国空军
First Lieutenant, United States Air Force.
你与苏联有什么联系吗
Do you have any association
鲍尔斯中尉
with the Soviet Union, Lieutenant Powers?
开玩笑吗
Kidding?
回答问题 中尉
Just answer the questions, Lieutenant.
用是或不是 尽量简洁
Yes, no, or as simply as you can.
你和苏联有什么联系吗
Do you have any association with the Soviet Union?
绝对 没有
Hell, no.
你知道为什么你来这吗
Do you know why you're here?
呃嗯
Mmm-mmm.
这算是否吗
Is that a no?
是 我是说
Yes. I mean...
不 就是 没有
No, it's just "no."
确实 我一点都不知道为什么我要在这
Yes, I have absolutely no idea why I'm here.
目视前方 中尉
Eyes front, Lieutenant.
好的 长官
Yes, sir.
你在那怎么样 加里
How'd you do in there, Gary?
挺好的 我觉得我应该证明了自己的清白
Pretty good. Think I got my name right.
那你很可能比西恩得分还高呢
You probably outscored Shinn, then.
谁要赢了
Who's winning?
啊 是我
Uh, that would be me.
好的 加我一个
Oh. Well, deal me in.
所以 这些东西就都是我的了
So, these are all mine, then.
我跟你们说过不要跟他玩
I told you boys not to play with him.
好了 飞行员们 事情是这样的
Okay, drivers, here's the deal.
你们被选中执行一项任务
You've been selected for a mission
这项任务你们不能与屋子之外的
which you are not to discuss
任何人提起
with anyone outside of this room.
一个都不能
No one.
我不管你信任谁
I don't care who you trust.
不管是妻子 妈妈 心上人
Wife, mother, sweetheart.
或者你每晚祈祷的神
The good Lord when you pray at night.
下面我将要讲的任何事
You don't tell any of them anything
你们一点都不能说
of what I'm about to tell you.
你们每个人 都达到了某种要求
Each of you drivers has met certain qualifications.
高度忠诚
High level security clearance.
出色飞行技术
Exceptional pilot ratings
驾驶单座飞机的飞行时间
in excess of the required hours flight time
达到了我们的要求
in a single-seat aircraft.
我们正卷入一场战争
We are engaged in a war.
这场战争 迄今为止 还是一场没有硝烟的战争
This war does not, for the moment, involve men-at-arms.
它是信息战
It involves information.
你们要去收集情报
You will be collecting information.
你们要去收集敌方情报
You will be gathering intelligence about the enemy.
你们收集到的信息 将为我们提供
The intelligence you gather could give us the upper hand
与苏联的热核战中的先机
in a full thermonuclear exchange with the Soviet Union.
或者能避免一场战争
Or it could prevent one.
对于公众来说
For public purposes,
对于你的妻子和母亲
as far as your wife or mother
或者是你的心上人 或者是神
or sweetheart or the good Lord above,
你们的任务是不存在的
your mission does not exist.
如果任务不存在 你们的身份也就不存在
If it does not exist, you do not exist.
你们不能被枪击 不能被逮捕
You cannot be shot down. You cannot be captured.
你们现在是中央情报局的人了
You work for the CIA now.
那么 吉姆 我听说你那位有假的口音
So, Jim, I heard your guy is speaking with a phony accent.
他能一直假装那样吗
Does he keep that up all the time?
事实上 我可以保证他一直都这么说话的
Actually, I'm pretty sure that's just the way he talks.
他用着俄国名字 但是拿着英国护照
He's got the Russian name but a British passport.
我怀疑那护照的真实性
Well, I doubt that that's genuine.
那么  吉姆 我们说到哪了
So, Jim, where are we? I see here...
是的 法官 你看
Yes, uh, Judge, you see,
我觉得三个星期弄不完这些
I just don't think that three weeks is going to do it, here.
你知道 我们有大量的证据
We... We got a massive amount of evidence, as you know.
你想延期吗
You wanna postpone?
给我六周吧
Six weeks.
我是说 基本上这只有我自己和我的同事在处理
I mean, there's just myself and my associate, basically.
吉姆 你是认真的吗
Jim, is this serious?
先生 您的意思是
Sir?
你是认真的吗
Is this serious?
是的 确实 我是认真的
Yes. Yes, indeed, it is.
您可以从档案中看到
You can see in the filing...
吉姆 这个人是苏联间谍
Jim, this man is a Soviet spy.
－他们说他是 －得了吧 律师
-Allegedly. -Come on, Counselor!
法官大人
Your Honor.
当然 我很敬重你
Of course, I salute you.
我们都很敬重你 因为你承担了这个不讨好的案子
We all salute you for taking on a thankless task.
这个人会拥有法定诉讼程序
This man has to have due process.
但是 我们就不在这糊弄对方了
But let's not kid each other.
他将会得到有力的辩护
He'll receive a capable defense.
然后 上帝保佑 他会被定罪
And, God willing, he'll be convicted.
得了吧 律师
Come on, Counselor.
我们别相糊弄对方了
Let's not play games with this.
在我的法庭上不行
Not in my courtroom.
我们定好了日子
We have a date
我们一定要进行审判
and we're going to trial.
出租车
Taxi!
我知道你是空车 混蛋
I see your light on! Son of a bitch.
我等不及要回曼哈顿了
Can't wait to get back to Manhattan.
他是空车呢 对吧
His light was on, right?
混球
Son of a bitch.
和他们的舒适度相违背
Against their level of comfort.
这条法规还是没变
The statute hasn't changed.
不好意思 先生
Oh, excuse me, sir.
很抱歉 不好意思 哦
Pardon me. Sorry. Oh!
多诺万先生
Mr. Donovan.
干嘛
What?
想干嘛
中央情报局
CIA.
是的
Yeah.
我只想跟您聊聊
I just wanted to chat.
案子进行的怎么样了
How's the case going?
进行得挺好 不能再好了
Case is going great. Couldn't be better.
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
你们谈过了吗
Has your guy talked?
什么意思
Excuse me.
你和他见面了 他说什么了吗
You met him. Has he talked? Has he said anything yet?
我们不该有这番对话
We're not having this conversation.
当然 当然要当我们没聊过
No, of course not.
不 我是说 我们真的不该聊
No, I mean, we really are not having it.
你现在是在要我违反律师和客户之间的保密协议
You're asking me to violate attorney-client privilege.
哦 得了吧 律师大人
Oh, come on, Counselor.
知道么 我以为像你这样的人
You know, I wish people like you
不会说 得了吧 律师大人这种话
would quit saying "Oh, come on, Counselor."
今天第一次发生的时候我就很不开心
I didn't like it the first time it happened today.
一个法官对我说了两次这话
A judge said it to me twice.
我越听越不不爽
And the more I hear it, the more I don't like it.
好吧 听着 我理解你有保密协议
Okay, well, listen, I understand attorney-client privilege.
我也知道所有的法律伎俩
I understand all the legal gamesmanship.
我也理解这是你的工作
And I understand that's how you make a living.
但我要说的是其他方面的事
But I'm talking to you about something else.
关于国家的安全
The security of your country.
如果我的表达方式冒犯了您 我感到抱歉
And I'm sorry if the way I put it offends you.
但是我们需要知道阿贝尔跟你说了什么
But we need to know what Abel is telling you.
你懂了吗 多诺万
You understand me, Donovan?
我们必须要知道
We need to know.
别用糊弄童子军那一套对付我
Don't go "Boy Scout" on me.
我们可以不择手段
We don't have a rule book, here.
你是霍夫曼探员 对吗
You're Agent Hoffman, yeah?
是的
Yeah.
德国血统
German extraction.
是的 所以呢
Yeah, so?
我的名字是多诺万 爱尔兰血统
My name's Donovan. Irish.
父母都是爱尔兰那边的
Both sides, mother and father.
我是爱尔兰儿女 你是德国后裔
I'm Irish, you're German.
但什么让我们都成为了美国人呢
But what makes us both Americans?
只有一件事
Just one thing.
一件事 唯一的一件事
One, one, one.
那就是规则之书
The rule book.
我们称之为宪法
We call it the Constitution
我们遵从那些规定
and we agree to the rules,
那让我们成为了美国公民
and that's what makes us Americans.
那是保障我们作为美国公民的所有
It's all that makes us Americans
所以不要告诉我你们没有规则
so don't tell me there's no rule book,
别冲我那样点头 你个混蛋
and don't nod at me like that, you son of a bitch.
我们是不是也得提防着你了
Do we need to worry about you?
只要我不被打扰 干我该干的 你就不用担心
Not if I'm left alone to do my job.
从此之后
From this moment forward
你们不能把U-2战机称为间谍飞机
you will not refer to the U-2 as a spy plane
或者是侦察机
or reconnaissance aircraft.
你们就把它称为 那个东西
You will refer to it as "The Article."
那个东西有80英尺的臂展
The Article  has an 80-foot wingspan.
它由一个普拉特和惠特尼J57 P-37发动机提供动力
It's powered by a single Pratt and Whitney J57 P-37 engine.
1万磅推力
10,000 pounds of thrust
最大时速430公里
and a maximum speed of 430 miles an hour.
她也许不是很快
She may not be quick,
但是鉴于你们在7万英尺的高空巡航
but at your cruising altitude of 70,000 feet,
没什么能够接近你们
nothing will come close to you.
7万
70,000?
关键就是敌人们不知道你们就在他们上空
The idea is the enemy doesn't even know you're there.
机翼看起来有点薄啊
It looks kind of flimsy.
每增重一磅就要付出降低一英尺的代价
Every extra pound of weight costs a foot in altitude,
而且我们还需要装照相机
and we need to accommodate the cameras.
那是三个4500毫米镜头
That's a 4,500-millimeter lens, times three.
一个针尖全景照相机
A pin-sharp panoramic camera
是我们以前用过的空中侦查相机的四倍厉害
four times as powerful as any aerial reconnaissance cameras we've ever used.
你们要照很多很多相片
You're gonna be taking pictures, lots of pictures.
在7万英尺的高空 这东西能够经一次掠过
At 70,000 feet, The Article can photograph
拍摄到2000平方米的领土
2,000 square miles of territory in one pass.
现在 飞行员们
Now, drivers,
苏美尔特工需要你们全神贯注
give Agent Sumner your undivided attention.
你们在任务中需要的东西就在这边
The items you will need on your mission are over here.
B型照相机 里维尔8代型号40胶卷盒
B camera, Revere 8 model 40 magazine,
梯形卡布里K-25 银质
Keystone Capri K-25, silver.
空心柄刮胡刀
Hollow-handle shaving brush.
在食用箔上有一整套密码表
Complete set of cipher tables on edible silver foil.
特制的拍照设备
Specialist photographic equipment.
好 我们 呃 我们懂了 谢谢
Yeah, we, uh... We get the idea. Thank you.
呃 不好意思 博斯克特工 布拉斯科特工
Uh, excuse me, Agent, uh, Bosco. "Blasco."
到
Sir.
好像这个单子上还有个项目
There seems to be a subsection to this list here.
大部分的东西是从他的工作室拿来的
Well, most of this stuff came from his studio,
剩下的是来自他住的酒店房间
but the rest is from the hotel room he was holed up in.
我们在那找到了他
Where we found him.
你搜查的那个酒店房间吗
The hotel room you searched?
嗯 是的
Well, yeah.
我能看下搜查证吗
Can I see the warrant?
什么
The what?
好吧 给我解释一下 当时是有搜查证的对吧
Yeah, explain this to me. There was a warrant.
是有委任状
There was a warrant.
一个公民拘留传票用来逮捕了一个外国人
A civil detention writ for the arrest of an alien,
但是却没有搜查证
but there was no search warrant
来搜查犯罪活动的嫌疑
for suspicion of criminal activity.
那么 搜查和证据
So, the search and the evidence
那是搜查的结果
that is the fruit of that search,
就全部都是玷污过的 且不能被承认的
that's all tainted and should not be admitted.
这个人需要什么法定诉讼程序啊 法官大人 这个人不是
What protections is he due, Your Honor? The man is not...
他是什么 他可是鲁道夫·伊万诺维奇·阿贝尔
The man is what? He's Rudolf Ivanovich Abel.
他是苏联公民
He is a Soviet citizen.
他不是美国人
He's not an American.
1886年 益和诉霍普金斯案
1886, Yick Wo v. Hopkins.
法院认为即使外国人 在那个案子里是中国移民
The court held that even aliens, in that case Chinese immigrants,
也不能被关押来回答犯罪问题 在没有法定诉讼程序的情况下
could not be held to answer for a crime without due process of law,
包括任何非法入境的外国人
including any alien that entered the country illegally.
司法部
The Department of Justice
对美国有第一效忠的义务
has its first allegiance to the United States.
我不认为一个外国人 如果他是非法入境的
I don't see how an alien, if he's here illegally,
他如何遭受了权利的剥夺
how he suffered deprivation of rights.
什么样的权利
Rights as what?
一个美国公民的权利吗
An American?
什么权利 律师
Rights as what, Counselor?
我们正处于一场文明战争中
We're in a battle for civilization.
这个俄国间谍来到这里 威胁我们的生活
This Russian spy came here to threaten our way of life.
现在 我有一法庭的人等着
Now, I have a courtroom of people waiting.
出去 坐到那个俄罗斯人边上
Get out there, sit beside the Russian.
让我们抓紧弄完这事
Let's get this over and done with.
还有你的请求被否决了
And your motion is denied.
他应该给自己多投点保险
He should take some insurance out on himself.
怎么样
How did we do?
在里面吗
In there?
嗯
Uh...
不太好
Not too good.
显然 你不是个美国公民
Apparently, you're not an American citizen.
确实
That's true.
而且据你上级所说
And according to your boss,
你也不是个苏联公民
you're not a Soviet citizen either.
好吧 上级不一定总是对的
Well, the boss isn't always right
但他永远是上级
but he's always the boss.
你从不担心吗
Do you never worry?
那会有帮助吗
Would it help?
起立
All rise.
我宣誓忠实干美利坚合众国国旗
"I pledge allegiance to the Flag
忠实于她所代表的合众国
"of the United States of America,
上帝之下一个不对分割的国家
"and to the Republic for which it stands,
在这里
"one Nation under God, indivisible,
人人享有自由和正义
"with liberty and justice for all."
首先 你必须知道
First, you have to know what happens
当一原子弹爆炸时会发生什么
when an atomic bomb explodes.
那会产生非常亮的闪光 比太阳还要亮
There is a bright flash, brighter than the sun.
它可以粉碎大厦 震碎所有的窗户
It can smash in buildings, break windows all over town.
但如果你像伯特一样 卧倒并掩护
But if you duck and cover like Bert,
你会安全很多
you will be much safer.
现在有两种袭击
There are two kinds of attack,
一种是带警告的 一种是不带的
with warning and without any warning.
嗯
Mmm.
怎么回事
What's going on in here?
爸爸 这很重要
Okay, Dad, this is really important.
当战争开始之后 他们做的第一件事
When the war begins, the first thing they do
是切断所有的水和电
is cut off all the water and all the electricity.
所以我们应该做得第一件事就是保证水是充足的
So the first thing we should do is keep this filled,
用你房间里的浴室
use the shower in your room,
用楼下的水箱 外面花园的软管
use the sink downstairs, the garden hose outside...
那些都是好主意
Those are good ideas.
但是 罗杰 我不认为
But, Roger, I don't see this
这是你需要担心的问题
as being something you ever have to worry about.
是 但等听到空袭警报的时候
Yeah, but when you hear the sirens,
那时可能就没有足够时间去填满浴缸和水箱了
there may not be enough time to fill the tub and the sinks.
不会有空袭警报的
Not gonna be any sirens...
这是什么
What is this?
当炸弹来的时候
When the bomb comes,
红卫军会瞄准帝国大厦
the Reds will aim for the Empire State Building.
但是炸弹会在1万英尺的高空爆炸
But the bomb goes off at 10,000 feet up.
生活杂志说 这叫空中爆炸
In Life magazine, it's called an airburst,
而且如果这个炸弹有50兆吨
and if the bomb is 50 megatons,
冲击波会不断扩散
the blast wave goes out and out and out
把从这里到这里的所有东西都毁掉
and melts everything from here to here.
包括我们住的地方 这里
Including where we live. Here.
是啊 就在那
Yeah, right there.
但 你要知道 罗杰
But, you know, Roger,
没人会对我们扔原子弹的
no one is dropping atomic bombs on us.
但是俄国人想啊
But the Russians want to.
你知道吗 你辩护的那个俄国人
You know that Russian guy you're defending?
他是先来这边为
He's here to get things ready
扔原子弹的人做好准备的
for the guys who drop the bombs.
不不 他不是 不是
No, no, he's not... Not here for that.
他其实都不是俄国人
He's not even Russian.
我们认为 他是在英国北部出生的
He was born, we think, in Northern England.
好吧 但他是俄国的间谍啊
Yeah, but he's a spy for Russia.
我都不知道你在做什么
I don't even understand what you're doing.
你不是共产党人啊 那你为什么要替共产党人辩护呢
You're not a Communist, so why are you defending one?
因为这是我的工作
Well, because it's my job.
才不是呢
It never used to be.
在美利坚合众国
In the case of the United States of America
控诉鲁道夫·阿贝尔这件案子上
versus Rudolf Abel,
对第一项控诉
as to the first count in the indictment,
你们如何裁决辩方
how do you find the defendant?
有罪或无罪
Guilty or not guilty?
有罪
Guilty.
第二项控诉
As to the second count?
有罪
Guilty.
第三项控诉
As to the third count?
有罪
Guilty.
法官大人 根据证据份量
Your Honor, I make a motion to set aside these guilty verdicts
我请求驳回这些有罪判决
against the weight of evidence.
否决
Denied.
陪审团可以离开
The jury is discharged.
感谢你们
Thank you all.
我想再说一句 如果我是你们其中一员
I would like to add that, if I were one of you,
我也会达成一样的判决
I would've reached the same verdict.
量刑将在
Sentencing will be
11月15日进行
November 15.
死刑不是板上钉钉的
The death sentence is not a foregone conclusion.
别担心
Don't worry.
我不怕死 多诺万先生
I'm not afraid to die, Mr. Donovan.
虽然
Although
它并不是我的第一选择
it wouldn't be my first choice.
你落了这个
You left this behind.
哦 谢谢
Oh, thank you.
哦 非常感谢
Oh, thank you very much!
你从未问过我那些控告是否是真的
You've never asked me if the charges were true.
我是不是真的是一个间谍
If I am indeed a spy.
这就是我们的处事方式
This is how we do it.
这个案子很重要
The case against you matters.
逼得他们证明很重要
Making them prove it matters.
虚构的就是
The fiction is...
你是不是真的做了 并不重要
Whether you did it or not doesn't matter.
国家必须证明 你就是个间谍
The state has to prove it, that you're a spy.
所以你一点都不好奇吗
So you're not curious?
不 一点都不
No, not really.
我一直把你当成一个艺术家
I always assumed you were an artist.
我的妻子 她是个艺术家
My wife, she's the artist.
她是个音乐家
She's a musician
在莫斯科儿童交响乐团
in the Children's Orchestra of Moscow.
演奏什么乐器的
What instrument?
竖琴
The harp.
哦
Oh.
那她就是个天使啊
Then, she's an angel.
你现在站着的样子 让我想到了
Standing there like that, you remind me of a man
一个以前我年轻时经常来我家的男人
who used to come to our house when I was young.
我父亲曾说 向他学着点
My father used to say, "Watch this man."
所以每次他来 我都注意着他
So I did, every time he came.
而每一次
And never once
他都没做什么出格的事
did he do anything remarkable.
而我让你想起了他
And I remind you of him?
有这么一次 我大概你儿子这么大的时候
This one time, I was about the age of your son.
我家被党派边境队给占领了
Our house was overrun by partisan border guards.
人很多
Dozens of them.
我父亲被打了 母亲被打了
My father was beaten, my mother was beaten,
还有这个男人 我父亲的朋友 也被打了
and this man, my father's friend, he was beaten.
然后我就看着这个男人
And I watched this man.
每一次他们打他
Every time they hit him
他就会重新站起来
he stood back up again.
所以他们下手就更重
So they hit him harder.
但 他还是会站起来
Still, he got back to his feet.
我想 这让他们最后放弃了殴打他
I think because of this they stopped the beating.
他们让他活下去了
They let him live.
我记得他们这么说
I remember them saying it.
大概的意思是
It sort of means, like, uh,
站着的人
"standing man."
Standing man.
－你好 吉姆 －米莉 你真美
-Hello, Jim! -Millie, you're a vision.
莫迪正在更衣呢
Mortie's busy getting kitted out.
进来吧
But come on in.
－苏格兰威士忌吗 吉姆 －哦 好的 谢谢
-Scotch, Jim? -Oh, yes, please. Thank you.
嗯 只要一点水
Uh, just a drop of water.
法官大人
Your Honor.
你好 吉姆 我正准备出门呢
Hello, Jim! Just going out.
但还有几分钟空
Got a few minutes though.
一个基金会的晚宴 米莉在里面很活跃
March of Dimes thing. Millie is active.
谢谢你能见我
Well, thank you for seeing me.
我想说几句关于量刑的事
I just wanted to give you my two cents on the sentencing.
然后我想也许我应该来您家来打扰下您
And I thought maybe I should pester you at home
因为我的一些看法不太合法
as not all of my points are narrowly legal.
好吧 这的确是那样一个案件
Yeah, well, it's that kind of case.
希望我在审讯的时候没有太草率
I hope I wasn't too scratchy during the trial
但就像你所说
but it's exactly what you say.
这件案件没什么是勉强合法的
Nothing about this is narrowly legal.
有更大的问题
There are bigger issues.
更大的
Bigger issues!
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
嗯
Uh...
法官大人
Sir...
我认为在考虑
I think it could be considered
美国的最大利益的情况下
in the best interests of the United States
阿贝尔应该活着
that Abel remain alive.
为什么
Why?
我不是说我已经决定好了
I'm not saying I've made up my mind
但如果他决定合作
but if he was gonna cooperate,
与政府部门合作 他早就已经做了
work with the government, he would've done it already.
－是 但是这里有个问题是 －你不能
-True, but the issue here... -You can't...
抱歉
Excuse me.
你不能说对于美国来说
You can't say it's in the best interest of the United States
他在监狱度过余生是最大利益
that he spend the rest of his days in a prison cell.
这怎么就国家利益了呢
How is this the national interest?
并不是监禁本身 法官大人
Not the incarceration itself, sir.
有可能 在可预见的未来
It is possible that, in the foreseeable future,
一个同等级别的美籍探员
an American of equivalent rank
可能被苏联政府抓住呢
might be captured by Soviet Russia.
我们可能会希望有个人质好做交换
We might want to have someone to trade.
哇
Wow.
那听起来就像不停在等待如果发生啊
That sounds like spinning what-ifs.
得等到母牛回家吧
You could do that till the cows come home.
这正是我干的事啊 如果 我可以是在保险行业的
It's my business, what-ifs. I'm in insurance.
而在这件事上 根本没有不可能
And there's nothing implausible about this one.
这完全是建立在可能的情况下
It's entirely in the realm of what could happen.
正是这个几率让人们愿意投保
It's the kind of probability that people buy insurance for.
如果我们给他判了死刑 我们就等于敞开大门
If we send this guy to his death, we leave ourselves wide open.
完全没有保险
No policy in our back pocket
为风暴来的那天做后备了
for the day the storm comes.
说得很好
Nice speech.
法官大人 你还要考虑人道主义方面的争论
Sir, there is also the humanitarian argument.
他应该为俄国派他来做的事情去死吗
Should he die for doing the job they sent him to do?
好了 律师
All right, Counselor.
我得走了
I gotta run.
很高兴见到你 吉姆
Good seeing you, Jim.
我送你出去吧
I'll walk you out.
起立
All rise.
美国纽约东区
The United States District Court
联邦地区法院 现在开庭
for the Eastern District of New York is now in session.
由莫蒂默·拜尔斯法官主持
The honorable Mortimer Byers presiding.
坐下
Be seated.
被告请起立
The defendant will please rise.
根据本法院裁判
In the measured judgment of this court
以下量刑
the following sentence,
基于陪审团对每一项
based upon the jury's verdict of guilty
控告的有罪判决
as to each count of the indictment,
是能够符合已阐述的考验
is believed to meet the test which has been stated.
依据全部罪名的有罪判决
Pursuant to the verdict of guilty as to all counts,
被告将交予
the defendant is committed to the custody
美国总检察长
of the Attorney General of the United States
监禁在他选择的
for imprisonment in a federal institution
联邦机构 30年
to be selected by him for a period of 30 years.
法警 你可以将被告收押了
Marshals, you may take the defendant into custody.
没 没有电刑吗
No... No electrocution?
没有 没有
No. No, no.
为什么我们没吊死他
Why aren't we hanging him?
以上帝的名义 为什么我们没吊死他
In the name of God, why aren't we hanging him?
坐下 先生
Sit down, sir!
他是个间谍啊 他用他的谎言在谋杀我们啊
He's a spy! He's killing us with his lies!
以上帝的名义 为什么我们没吊死他
In the name of God, why aren't we hanging him?
就是
That's right!
他是个间谍
He's a spy!
多诺万先生 多诺万先生
Mr. Donovan! Mr. Donovan!
就一个问题 一个问题 先生
Just one question. Just one question, sir.
我的帽子 我的帽子
My hat! My hat! My hat!
没人回发表意见
Nobody here has a comment.
多诺万先生和太太将不会回答任何问题
Mr. and Mrs. Donovan are not answering questions.
现在这个全国性的噩梦已经结束
How do you feel now that
你们有什么感觉
this national nightmare is over?
多诺万先生 你对判决结果满意吗
Mr. Donovan, are you happy with the verdict?
我们 我们坚定我们会上诉
We're... We're in firm ground on, uh, for a case on appeal.
－上诉 －是的 上诉
-Appeal? -Appeal, yes.
吉姆 你做得很棒
Jim, you did a great job.
你履行了你的委托 而且还远不止此
You fulfilled your mandate and then some.
但这个男人是个间谍
But the man is a spy.
判决是正确的 根本没有什么理由给你去上诉
The verdict is correct and there's no reason to appeal it.
有很多程序方面的理由
There's ample procedural reason.
我们都知道搜查是被玷污了的
We know the search is tainted.
还有第四修正案
And Fourth Amendment issues
始终在一个上诉法庭里面更有影响
will always weigh more heavily in an appellate forum.
我们有很大几率赢的
We've got a good shot.
你到底在说什么啊
What the goddamn hell are you talking about?
我们应该展示他得到了有力的辩护 我们也的确做了
We were supposed to show he had a capable defense, which we did.
你为什么给我引用什么该死的宪法条例啊
Why are you citing the goddamn Constitution at me?
汤姆 如果你正视我的眼睛
Tom, if you look me in the eye
告诉我 我们没有任何理由
and tell me we don't have grounds
去上诉 那我就会放弃
for an appeal, I'll drop it right now.
我不是这个意思 你知道我指的是什么
I'm not saying that. You know what I'm saying.
汤姆是说上诉是有代价的
Tom is saying there's a cost to these things.
正是
That's right.
那个代价会把你的家庭和你的事务所都赔进去的
A cost to both your family and your firm.
我太想念音乐了
I've missed music.
他们检查过收音机 确保没有发报机在里面
They checked the radio to make sure there was no transmitter in it.
我很确定他们干了
I'm sure they did.
－肖斯塔科维奇 －嗯
-Shostakovich. -Mmm.
那是个非常伟大的艺术家 肖斯塔科维奇
That's a very great artist, Shostakovich.
嗯 我认为
Uh, I think
我们最有力的逆转根据
our strongest grounds for reversal
是宪法级别的
are constitutional.
我们最好机会是如果高级法院同意复审我们的案件
Our best chance is if the Supreme Court agrees to review our case.
吉姆
Jim...
你要小心
You should be careful.
非常小心
Careful.
77号日落大道
77 Sunset Strip
爱德华·伯恩
Edward Byrnes.
77号日落大道
77 Sunset Strip
以及理查德·朗
And Richard Long.
早上好 苏珊
Good morning, Suzanne.
早上好 迪克
Good morning, Dick.
有你的一封特殊信件
There is a special delivery letter here for you.
哦 她啊
Oh, her.
妈妈
Mom!
发生什么了
What in God's name happened?
亲爱的 你没事吧
Honey, are you all right?
－妈妈 －你受伤了吗
-Mom! -Are you hurt?
我看着她 去看看楼上
I've got her. Upstairs!
－你们还好吗 －爸爸 我靠着墙坐呢
-Are you all right?  -I sat with my back against the wall, Dad!
你还好吗 你没事吧
Are you okay? Are you all right?
爸爸 我靠着墙坐呢
Dad, I sat with my back against the wall!
－好的 好的 －远离窗户呢
-Good, good. -Away from the windows!
好的 好的 好的
Good, good, good, good, good.
好孩子 好孩子
Good boy, good boy, good boy.
好了 没事了
It's okay. It's all right.
没事了 他们走了 他们走了
It's all right, they're gone, they're gone.
他们都是懦夫 他们走了
They're cowards. They're gone.
我们已经让刑警搜查附近一带了
We have detectives canvassing the neighborhood.
也许我们能得到那辆车的详细描述
Maybe we'll find a description of the car
但我觉得希望不大
but I don't think it's very likely.
我们需要保护
We're gonna need protection.
哦 我已经下令让两辆警车留在这里了
Oh, I have instructions to leave two cars here.
很明显
It'll be pretty obvious
－这会是保全 －多久
-that this is a secure... -For how long?
这周晚些时候我必须去趟华盛顿
I have to be in Washington later on this week.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
看看你对你的家庭做了什么
What are you doing to your family?
什么 警官
Pardon me, Officer?
你还在给那家伙辩护吗
You're still defending this guy?
你为他辩解有什么好处呢
I mean, what are you fighting for him for?
好了 别讲了 警官
Okay, knock that off, Officer.
我怎么不能讲了
I'll knock off nothing.
我曾是第三部队降落在奥马哈海滩
I was in the third wave at Omaha Beach.
嘿 我也服过役的
Hey, I did my time in the service.
我曾经与这些俄国人打仗 现在你倒给他们做辩护起来了
I was fighting these guys, and you're defending them?
你为什么不就好好做一个执法人员该做的事呢
Why don't you just do your job as an officer of the law?
好吧 对不起 我们出去吧 走吧
Okay, I'm sorry. Let's go outside. Come on.
你知道吗 忘了他说的吧
You know what? Just forget him.
我到底哪儿理解错了
What am I not getting here?
出去 警官 我很抱歉
Outside, Officer. I'm sorry.
为一个共产间谍辩护 苍天
Defending a commie spy. Jeez!
你就不觉得这是你自找的吗 先生
Do you feel that you deserve this, sir?
如果在苏联领空
Should it become necessary
需要弃机
to abandon the aircraft over Soviet territory,
这有个2.5磅的炸药包
then there's a two-and-a-half pound explosive charge
在机身里边
contained within the fuselage.
首先 你激活电路
Now, first, you activate the circuits.
但要开启一个70秒的计时器
But to start the 70-second timer,
你需要打开标记着 自毁 的开关
you need to flip the switch marked "Destruct."
这些飞行任务保持机密
It is imperative that these flights remain a secret
以及这个装置不落入敌人手中是绝对必要的
and this equipment does not fall into enemy hands.
那我们怎么办
What about us?
我不知道你是否在开玩笑 鲍尔斯中尉
I don't know if you're kidding, Lieutenant Powers.
我可没有
I'm not.
你们对飞机所知的一切
What you know about the plane
和飞机一样是机密
is as secret as the plane itself.
如果被俘获是必然结局
If capture is a foregone conclusion,
你和你的飞机一起坠毁
you go down with your plane.
现在 如果你们觉得你可以跳机 并逃走
Now, if you think you can ditch and get away,
如果你在国境边界 那没问题
if you're close enough to a border, fine.
你们都知道跳机程序的
You know the ejection protocol.
但如果跳了
But if you ditch,
记得带着这个硬币
you bring the dollar with you.
好吧 这里有根针
All right, there's a pin inside.
在你皮肤随意处划拉一下 里面饿毒性是即时的
You scratch your skin anywhere, it's instantaneous.
如果你认为你要被抓住了
If you think you are about to be captured,
你就用它
you use it.
飞行员们 听懂了吗
Drivers, you understand me?
用掉它
Spend the dollar.
首席法官大人 以及庭上 请允许我
Mr. Chief Justice, and may it please the court.
冷战不仅仅只是个措辞 法官大人
The "Cold War" is not just a phrase, Your Honor.
它不仅仅只是一种比喻
It's not just a figure of speech.
真实地 一场战争
Truly, a battle is being fought
正在世界上两个不同观点的国家之间打响
between two competing views of the world.
我主张鲁道夫·伊万诺维奇·阿贝尔
I contend that Rudolf Ivanovich Abel,
阿贝尔上校 正如他被叫的
"Colonel Abel," as he was called
甚至是被逮捕他的人
even by the men who arrested him,
是这场战役里面的敌人
is our foe in that battle.
辅助电源
Auxiliary power?
连上 启用
Connected and on.
座位氧气供给
Oxygen seat-pack supply?
供给1800磅每平方英寸
Supply at 1,800 psi.
变频器
Inverter?
开了 灯灭了
On, light out.
在那场战争中 他被作为一个战士所对待
He was treated as a combatant in that war
直至我们的政府不再合适去如此对待他
until it no longer suited our government to so treat him.
因此
Accordingly,
他并没有被给予 我们对待自己国民的保护
he was not given the protections we give our own citizens.
他遭受了
He was subjected to treatment that,
适用于敌军
however appropriate for a suspected enemy,
却不适用于一个犯罪嫌疑人的对待
was not appropriate to a suspected criminal.
燃料转输
Fuel transfer?
转输已关
Transfer switch off.
爆炸装置
Destructor?
爆炸保险装置
Destructor safety.
加载数据卡
Climb data card.
机身已安装
Installed in aircraft.
我了解这个人
I know this man.
如果控告是真的 他为外国势力效力 但他也忠实地效力了
If the charge is true, he serves a foreign power but he serves it faithfully.
如果他是对方军队的一名士兵 他就是一名好战士
If he is a soldier in the opposing army, he is a good soldier.
他并没有为救自己 而逃离战场
He has not fled the field of battle to save himself.
他拒绝为逮捕者效力
He has refused to serve his captor.
他拒绝背叛自己的事业
He has refused to betray his cause.
他拒绝做一个懦夫
He has refused to take the coward's way out.
一个懦夫必定早在逃离战场之前
The coward must abandon his dignity
抛弃自己的尊严
before he abandons the field of battle.
但 鲁道夫·阿贝尔绝不这么做
That, Rudolf Abel will never do.
我们难道不应该
Shouldn't we,
给予他
by giving him the full benefit
定义了我们政体的全部权利
of the rights that define our system of government,
展示给他看我们是谁
show this man who we are?
我们是谁
Who we are.
这不就是我们在这场冷战中拥有的最棒的武器吗
Is that not the greatest weapon we have in this Cold War?
和他比起来 我们会拥护我们自己的事业
Will we stand by our cause less resolutely
较不坚定些吗
than he stands by his?
总统宣布
The President announced
四天前 一架宇航局天气象侦查机消失在土耳其北部
that a NASA weather plane disappeared four days ago north of Turkey.
航天局怕
And the Space Administration fears
其飞行员在坠机中丧生
that its pilot died in the crash.
雷达探测显示飞机偏离了运行轨道
Radar showed the plane wandering off course
在联络断开前 飞机正在苏联领空
deep into Soviet territory before contact was lost,
这使得回收飞机
complicating any effort to recover it
或者飞行员的遗体变得相当困难
or the remains of the pilot.
现在 报道来自华盛顿的新闻
Now to news out of Washington.
在今天的投票中
In a close vote today,
最高法院已经确认了
the Supreme Court affirmed the conviction
对俄国间谍鲁道夫·伊万诺维奇·阿贝尔的判决
of Russian spy Rudolf Ivanovich Abel,
5票对4票
five votes to four.
此案提出了公民自由的问题
The case presented civil liberties issues,
据俄国被告的律师 詹姆斯·B·多诺万所说
according to the Russian's lawyer, James B. Donovan.
当问及他对今日的败诉有何感想时
When asked how he felt about today's loss,
多诺万先生只是说了 累了
Mr. Donovan simply said, "Tired."
广告之后 我会为您带来更多新闻
I'll have more news for you after this message.
造型小诀窍
Styling tricks
结束了
It's over.
看看新的 令人激动的造型小诀窍吧
See the new, exciting styling tricks
你
You...
马蒂
Marty.
如果找不到保诚案子的文件 我就麻烦了
I'll be damned if I can find the file on that Prudential case.
我 嗯 沃特斯先生让我把它交给杰克·艾域士办公室了
I, uh, Mr. Watters had me move it over to Jack Elwes's office
包括上诉的初稿
along with the first draft of the appeal.
他让你这么做了
He did?
是的 他重新起稿 然后上星期你在华盛顿的时候就把它归档了
Yeah, he redrafted and filed that last week while you were in Washington.
我们已经共事多久了
How long have we been together?
你弄得我好像从来不能完成交易一样
You act as if I've never closed a deal.
安排一个会面 挑个好点的地方
Set up a meeting. Someplace fancy.
我打赌杨先生会喜欢一些
I'm betting Mr. Young would like some of the finer things
纽约出品的出色的菜肴
New York has to offer.
然后 我希望你能给我那个概要
And I want you to give me the summary of...
你认识任何莱比锡市的人吗
Do you know anyone from Leipzig?
莱比锡市 我现在都能收到德国的恐吓信了吗
"Leipzig." Am I getting hate mail from Germany now?
是来自东德的
From East Germany.
是你的妻子吗
Is it your wife?
不是
No.
不不不不
No, no, no, no.
她假装是 但这都不是个好伪装
She pretends to be but it's not even a good pretense.
我冒昧写信给你
"I'm taking this liberty to write to you
在看到报纸上报道
"after having learned from the newspapers
关于你对我挚爱的丈夫
"about your most humane attitude
鲁道夫·阿贝尔 表达的人道态度
"towards my beloved husband, Rudolf Abel."
我要回信吗
And do I write back?
回吧 回
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
当你不知道怎么回事时 什么才是下一步呢
What's the next move when you don't know what the game is?
弗朗西斯·加里·鲍尔斯
Francis Gary Powers...
基于苏维埃社会主义共和国联盟法律第二条
On the strength of Article Two of the U.S.S.R. law
对政治犯罪的刑事责任
on criminal responsibility for state crimes
处以10年监禁
to 10 years of confinement
前三年必须关押于监狱
with the first three years to be served in prison.
刑法期限
The term of the punishment,
包括候审羁押
including preliminary detention,
将从1960年5月1日起
shall be counted from May first,
实行
nineteen hundred and sixty.
多诺万先生 非常感谢你能来
Mr. Donovan, thank you so much for coming.
很高兴见到你 杜勒斯先生
It's a pleasure to meet you, Mr. Dulles.
是我的荣幸 先生
It's an honor, sir.
雀巢咖啡 加奶 两块糖
Nescafe, cream, two lumps.
谢谢
Thank you.
你收到的这封信
Okay, this letter you received.
看起来显然苏联正在提出一个提案
Seems pretty clear that the Soviets are making an overture here.
他们通过东德来表示
They're doing it through East Germany
因为他们仍然不愿意承认阿贝尔是一位苏联公民
because they still don't want to acknowledge Abel as a Soviet citizen,
更别说苏联间谍了 所以
much less a Soviet spy. So...
各种虚构发生着呢
Lot of fiction going on.
是的 先生 但是到什么程度呢
Yes, sir, but to what end?
他们抓了我们的人 我们的间谍飞行员
They got our guy, our spy pilot.
我们有他们的人
We've got their guy.
交换犯人 我猜这是他们想要的
Prisoner exchange, I think that's what they're after.
这对你来说肯定不是个惊喜吧 律师
Which could hardly be a surprise to you, Counselor.
我认为 你预测到了这个可能性
It's an eventuality that I think you foresaw.
是的 我的确有这样想过 虽然我很少猜对
Yes, I sure did, and I'm so rarely right.
喔 那恭喜你 值得纪念
Well, congratulations. Red letter day.
现在我方也有一个人被抓 叫鲍尔斯
Now, we have our man over there. Powers.
是好人 脑子里装的全是机密信息
Good man, but with a head full of classified information.
阿贝尔的脑子里也全是机密
Abel has a head full of classified information, too,
但他一点儿也没告诉我们
but he hasn't given us a lick.
相信我 长官 他不会的
And, sir, take it from me, he won't.
是的 我们知道 但俄国人不那么想
Yes, we know that, but the Russians don't.
他们想在他招供之前要回他们的人
They want their man back before he cracks.
因为同样的理由 我们也想要回鲍尔斯
And we want Powers back for the same reasons.
长官 我想你的意思是
I think you are saying, sir,
最后每个人都会有一个好的结局
that there might be a happy ending for everyone.
是的 如果我们纵容他们的胡编乱造的话
Yes, if we, um, indulge their fiction.
我们希望你去同他们谈判 交换人质
We want you to negotiate the swap
因为你是一位普通公民
because you're a private citizen,
不是政府之间的谈话
so it's not governments talking.
他们不承认阿贝尔是苏联公民
They don't acknowledge Abel as a Soviet citizen,
我们不承认东德是一个主权国家
and we don't acknowledge East Germany as a sovereign country.
因为苏联在1945年将东柏林吞并
We haven't recognized East Berlin
并没有得到承认
since it was annexed by the Soviets in '45.
所以我的角色是谈判者 代表了
So I act as a negotiator, representing...
你不代表任何人
You're not representing anybody.
你也不是政府人员
Not a government official.
你没有官方身份
You have no official standing.
意思是 我方也虚构了一些事实
So, some fiction on our side as well.
是的
Correct.
也就是说 如果情况不利
Which means, of course, you can't rely on any acknowledgment
你得不到任何承认和帮助
or help if things go south.
中情局不会对此负责
CIA can't be responsible.
我们不能陷入尴尬局面
We can't be embarrassed.
他们想在哪里谈判
Where do they want this negotiation to take place?
在那儿
There.
那儿
"There"?
东柏林
East Berlin.
喔 东柏林的局势不是很
Well, isn't East Berlin getting rather...
的确 那里的局势正变得复杂起来
Oh, yes, the place is getting complicated.
的确 很复杂
Yeah, complicated.
过去几个月 苏联一直在设立检查站
The Soviet side has been setting up checkpoints for the past few months
想要阻止人员大量流失到西柏林
to try to stop people hemorrhaging to the Western sectors,
但并未奏效
and it hasn't worked.
据情报显示
We have intelligence to suggest
他们打算进一步采取措施
that they may go one step further
将整个东部地区隔离
and wall off the entire Eastern sector.
好了 就是这样
Okay, that's it in a nutshell.
决定权在于你
The decision is entirely yours.
你需要时间考虑一下
You need time to kick it around.
不
No.
我不用考虑了
No, I don't.
喔 好 很好
Well, fine. Fine.
这一切最好都保密
Best that this all remains confidential.
谁都不能说 包括你的妻子玛丽 或者是其他任何人
Let's not discuss any of this with, uh, Mary or with anyone else.
只与我们保持通信
Share the correspondence only with us.
告诉我们他们会在何时做什么
Let us know what they want to do and when.
我没有委托人 没有妻子 没有国家
I've got no client, no wife, no country.
也不知道什么时候会做什么 或者为谁效力
Don't know what I'm doing or when or who for.
你在为你的国家效力
You're doing it for your country,
但你的国家目前还不知道
but your country doesn't know that yet.
那我的当事人呢 这场交易中的另一个人 我的人
What about my client, the other person in this equation? My guy?
你的人 你是指那个俄国人吗
Your guy? You mean the Russian?
他不再是你的当事人了 律师
He's not your guy anymore, Counselor.
现在你的当事人是弗朗西斯·加里·鲍尔斯
Your guy is Francis Gary Powers now.
那我该怎么对鲁道夫·阿贝尔说
What do I tell Rudolf Abel?
告诉他不要死了
Tell him not to drop dead.
教授
Professor?
父亲去学校了
Papa went to university.
你不该来这儿 弗雷德里克
You shouldn't be here, Frederic.
他们今天还有课吗
They're having classes today?
他去学校看一看
He went to see. That's where he goes.
你来这干什么
What are you doing here?
我来接你和你父亲
I came to get you and your father.
你们必须和我在一起 明天可能就出不去了
You have to come with me. You might not get out tomorrow.
就 就走了吗
Just... Just leave?
是的是的是的 走 现在立刻
Yes. Yes, yes, yes, leave. Right now.
回去 回去
Go back. Go back.
我会没事的 我是美国人 你快回去
I'll be okay, I'm American. Go back.
去找你父亲 我会再想办法 你先走
Go back to your father's. We'll find another way. Go.
站住 你是谁
Anhalten! Wer bist du?
站住
Anhalt!
我没有过界 我住在这儿
Ich bin unverabschiedet! Ich wohn hier!
站住
Stopp!
嘿
Hey!
呃 你好
So, hi.
请出示证件
Papers, please.
我是学生 叫弗雷德里克·普莱尔
Ich bin Student Frederic Pryor.
是的 学生
Yes, Student.
那这个呢
Und das hier?
不准拍照
Keine Fotos!
我的名字叫弗雷德里克·普莱尔 我是学经济学的学生
My name's Frederic Pryor. I'm an economics student.
看 这是我的专题论文 论文
See? It's my dissertation. My thesis.
呃 毕业论文
Uh......Diplomarbeit
你听我说 看
You see? Look, look.
题目是 欧洲共产主义国家的外贸系统 哈
Look "The foreign trade system of the European Communist nations." Huh?
共产主义者？
Kommunisten? Ja?
花了很多精力
It was a lot of work.
共产主义者
Kommunisten
不要 那是我唯一的复本
No, that's my only copy.
不
No!
告诉我
Tell me something.
这是最后一分钟才做的决定
It came up at the last minute.
他们在伦敦有办事处
They have offices in London.
这些委托人 不是我的主意
These clients. Not my idea.
去苏格兰 是一次钓鱼探险
Scotland, this fishing expedition.
吉姆 是一次什么样的钓鱼之旅
What kind of fishing trip, Jim?
钓的是鲑鱼
Salmon fishing.
告诉我你不会有任何危险
Just tell me that you're not gonna be in any danger,
只是一次例行的商务旅行
that this is just a routine business trip,
我就不会担心了
and I won't worry.
我的护照
I need my passport.
给我一些坚持下去的理由吧
Just give me something to hold on to.
我不在乎真相
I don't even care if it's the truth.
我此行是为了我们
I'm doing this for us.
这位米歇纳先生是你在柏林的护卫
Mr. Michener, here, is your Berlin escort.
他是美国大使馆的使馆随员
He's an attache with the U.S. embassy.
－事情越来越复杂了 －啊哈
-So, it's gotten goddamn complicated. -Uh-huh.
正如你所知道的 最后一封信是来自阿贝尔太太
As you know, the last letter from Mrs. Abel,
不管她是谁 她去和东柏林的律师谈过了
whoever she is, talks about a lawyer in East Berlin,
也不管沃格尔先生是谁 反正代表的都是她的利益
Mr. Vogel, whoever he is, representing her interests, she says.
是的 沃格尔说
Yeah, Vogel says
他去了俄国驻东柏林大使馆
he's gone to the Russian embassy in East Berlin
他们已经准备好了要用鲍尔斯换阿贝尔
and they may be ready to trade Abel for Powers.
但是没人知道谁是哪国人
But no one knows who's who,
但是本质上他们都是俄国人 对吗
but essentially they're all Russian, right?
嗯 苏联 我们是这么认为的
Well, Soviet. Well, we think so.
你什么意思 我们可以把车里的暖气打开吗
What do you mean? Could we turn up the heat in here?
出了一个小问题
There's a wrinkle.
他们可能会给你扔个曲线球
They might try to throw you a curve ball.
试着让你接受另外一名犯人 而不是鲍尔斯
Try and get you to accept another prisoner other than Powers.
也是美国人
Another American?
额 东德国家安全局抓了一名美国学生
The, uh, East German Stasi picked up an American student.
叫弗雷德里克·普莱尔
Frederic Pryor.
他们发现他站到了柏林墙另一边去
Uh, the kid they found on the wrong side of the Wall.
他是耶鲁的研究生
He's a grad student out of Yale.
－来柏林学经济 －嗯嗯
Came over here to study economics. - Mmm-hmm.
所以 他们扬言说这孩子在从事间谍活动
So, they're making noises about trying this kid for espionage.
严重犯罪 可判死刑
Grave offense, capital crime. Well.
然后沃格尔联系到我们 说要做普莱尔的代理律师
Vogel got in touch with us, said he represents Pryor.
等等 你是说沃格尔要做阿贝尔太太和这孩子的代理律师
Wait a minute. Vogel represents Mrs. Abel and this... This kid?
是的 他真忙
Yeah, he's busy.
喔 那他是哪里人
Well, so, what is he?
沃格尔 他是东德人还是俄国人
Vogel, is he, uh, East German or is he Russian?
这个 等你见到他的时候自己分辨吧
Well, try to figure it out when you meet him.
地点在东柏林的俄国大使馆 时间是明天中午
At Russian embassy, East Berlin, noon tomorrow.
霍夫曼会告诉你怎样去
Hoffman will show you how to get there.
等等 告诉我 会有人护送我
Wait, show me how to get there? I'm gonna have an escort.
不是吗
Right?
喔 计划是那样的 但是就像我之前说的 出了一些小问题
Well, that was the plan but like I said, there's a wrinkle.
我不会带你去 已经决定了
I won't be taking you. Decision's been made.
美国政府方面不会有政府人员跨境 除非另有通知
No U.S. government personnel are to cross the border until further notice.
－为什么 －太危险了
-How come? -It's too dangerous.
东德人抓了这个孩子
Yeah, the East Germans grabbed this kid.
我们无法预料其中的免罚程度
There's a degree of impunity that we had not anticipated.
关键就是东德的议程和俄国议程
The point is that the East German agenda and the Russian agenda
可能不一样
may not be the same thing.
尝试去弄明白 然后照做
Try and figure it out and act accordingly.
然后尽量达成交易 用阿贝尔换鲍尔斯
And try to make a deal. Powers for Abel.
那 这个叫做普莱尔的大学生怎么办
Well, what about this college kid, Pryor?
不不 不要上当
Mmm-mmm. Don't fall for that.
我们可以再选一个时间救出他
We can get him out another time.
鲍尔斯才是关键
Powers is the whole ball game.
你的房间在哪儿
Where's your room?
我住在希尔顿酒店
I'll be staying at the Hilton.
不远
It's not far.
这是你可以在西柏林拨打的号码
This is a number here in West Berlin.
记住 然后还给我
Memorize it and give it back to me.
不不 我的意思是现在就记住
No, no. I... I mean, now.
苏联切断了国际线
The Soviets keep cutting the international lines
但本地通话是可以的
but local calls are okay.
会有人24小时接听
Someone will pick up day and night.
你护照上的这个签条
Now, this docket attached to your passport will serve as your ticket
是你进出苏联东部区域的凭证
into and out of the Eastern Soviet sector.
同沃格尔的会面安排在明天中午
The meeting with Vogel is set for noon tomorrow.
只剩几条线路可以到东柏林
There are only a few routes left to the East.
你坐城铁去 我们在路上指给你看过车站了
You take the S-Bahn, the station we showed you on the way in.
然后你到这儿的弗里德里希站下车
You're gonna get off at the Friedrichstrasse station here
步行到位于菩提树大道的苏联大使馆
and walk to the Soviet embassy on Unter den Linden here.
你现在看看地图 不能带在身上
Look at the map now. You shouldn't take it with you.
如果发现你在看地图 就知道你是美国人 被判定为间谍
You're looking at a map, you're an American, you're a spy.
然后你就很可能被拘留
You could well be detained.
避免与人交流
Just avoid interacting with people generally.
你不 你不是这儿的人 所以不要被认出来
You don't... You don't belong, so don't stick out.
那儿食物短缺 人心已经开始四分五裂
Food is scarce over there and things have started to fall apart.
有很多帮派
There are gangs,
那儿法律条例也不太稳固
and rule of law is less firmly established over there.
最后 一定要远离那堵墙
And definitely stay away from the Wall.
他们那边 有一条线
On their side, there's a line
沿墙的建筑都被拆除
cleared of buildings along the Wall.
他们称这条线为 生死线
They call it the "Death Line."
一旦跨过去 就会被射杀
Cross it and you'll be shot.
如果我既没有被拘留 也没有被射杀 结果会是什么呢？
Is there any outcome here where I'm not either detained or shot?
不要太担心米歇纳所说的
Don't worry too much about what Michener said.
不 我是在担心你所说的
No, I'm worried about what you're saying.
普莱尔
This kid, Pryor,
东德人抓的那个孩子 他多大年龄？
that the East Germans have, how old is he?
25岁 怎么了
Twenty-five. Why?
和道基一样大
Same age as Dougie.
谁
Who?
我的一个同事
Eh, an associate of mine.
弗雷德里克·普莱尔
Frederic Pryor.
不好意思 我不能再帮你了
Tut mir leid. Ich kann Ihnen nicht weiter helfen.
对此我无可奉告
Ich kann Ihnen dazu nichts sagen.
他不在这儿？
Er ist nicht hier?
还是你不能告诉我他在哪？
Oder Sie können mir nicht sagen, wo er ist?
他在哪？
Wo ist er?
对此我无可奉告
Ich kann Ihnen dazu nichts sagen.
求你了
Bitte
求你告诉我
Bitte sagen Sie es mir.
求你了 我一定要知道
Bitte, ich muss es wissen.
还有别的什么可以跟我说的人吗
Gibt es jemand, mit dem ich sonst reden kann?
求你告诉我
Bitte sagen Sie es mir.
在哪里 他在哪里？
Wo? Wo ist er?
回到队伍里去
Gehen Sie in die Reihe!
请您回到队伍里面去
Bitte zurück gehen Sie in die Reihe!
你以为你是谁？赶紧回到队伍里去
Was glauben Sie ,wer Sie sind? Gehen Sie sofort in die Reihe!
好好好
Okay, okay, okay.
你在这儿干什么
Was machen Sie hier?
请回到队伍里面去
Bitte zurück in die Reihe!
怎么了
Was ist hier los?
你听不懂我说话吗 请回到队伍里面去
Verstehen Sie mich nicht? Bitte in die Linie zurück!
证件怎么样
Bei dem Ausweis?
这是我的 我的护照
Das ist meine, mein Pass.
还有这是我的钱包
Und, und hier ist mein, meine Brieftasche.
你以为你是谁
Was glauben Sie, wer Sie sind?
通融一下，拜托
Mitteilen bitte.
拜托
Bitte
美国人？
Amerikaner?
美国人
Amerikaner.
护照没问题
Pass ist in Ordnung.
签证没问题
Visa ist korrekt.
你可以过去
Sie dürfen durch.
谢谢
Danke
早上好
Guten Morgen
请继续往前走
Aufstießen bitte weiter.
你迷路了吗
Bist du dich verlaufen
你好
Guten Tag
你知道迷路意味着什么吗
Weißt du, was Verlaufen heißt?
迷路
verlaufen
对对 这里的路
Ja ja, die uh, die Routen der Länder
这是哪种流浪汉呢
Was wissen Sie von Streunern?
正派的美国流浪汉啊
Feine amerikanicher Streuner.
问他有没有钱
Frag mal, ob er Geld hat.
你会说德语吗
Sprichst du deutsch?
会说 会说 我会说一点点德语
Ja ja, ich spreche etwas.
如果有所冒犯 我们道歉
So, we apologize if this offends.
但是
Aber
我真的也想要这么好的大衣
ich möchte auch echt gerne so einen tollen Mantel haben
呃 大衣
Uh... Coat?
我可以穿吗
Kann ich, kann ich ihn anziehen?
你要把大衣脱下来 他要穿
Du solltest den Mantel ausziehen. Er möchte ihn anprobieren!
过会儿还给你 一定还给你
Der dann gibt noch zurück, versprochen.
我们从你的钱包里借钱
Wir können uns Geld aus deiner Brieftasche leihen,
或者
oder
你把大衣给我们
du gibst uns den Mantel.
不花费你任何东西
Das kostet dir nichts.
好吧
Okay.
菩提树下大街
Unter den Linden,
这个地方在哪
Wo das ist?
直走
Du gehst gerade aus,
下一个路口右转
dann rechts,
然后在第二个路口左转
und die zweite links.
－你能听懂英文吗 －能 先生
-Do you understand English? -Yes, sir.
我是詹姆斯·多诺万 我来这见沃格尔先生
I'm James Donovan. I'm here to meet a Mr. Vogel.
－沃格尔先生 －他不在这儿工作
-Mr. Vogel. -He doesn't work here.
我只知道我应该在这见他
I'm just supposed to meet him. That's all I know.
多诺万先生
Mr. Donovan!
我们终于见到你了
So we finally meet you.
我是海伦·阿贝尔
I'm Helen Abel.
－我的丈夫怎么样了 － 喔 他很好
-How is our husband? -Oh. He's fine.
我的鲁道夫怎么样了
How is my Rudolf?
和你期望的一样好
As good as can be expected.
会让他回来了 对吗
And we will get him back, yes?
－这是我们的女儿 －你好吗
-This is our daughter. -How do you do?
莉迪亚
Lydia.
你是沃格尔先生吗
Are you Mr. Vogel?
不不不
No, no, no!
我不是沃格尔
I'm not Vogel.
我是表哥朱斯
I'm cousin Drews.
这是鲁道夫挚爱的表哥 朱斯
This is Rudolf's beloved cousin Drews.
－是的 表哥朱斯 －我是表哥朱斯
-Yes, cousin Drews. -I am cousin Drews.
表哥朱斯 好的
Cousin Drews, yes.
我是海伦·阿贝尔
I'm Helen Abel.
什么时候可以见到他
When will you see him?
你们的政府什么时候释放他
When will your government release him?
我有一点糊涂了
I'm a little, uh, lost here.
我是来见沃格尔先生的
I'm supposed to meet a Mr. Vogel.
噢 沃格尔先生是我们的律师
Oh, Mr. Vogel is our lawyer.
我们要进行协商 呃 协商交换
We were supposed to negotiate, uh, the exchange.
－把鲁道夫带回来 －是 是的 把他带回来
-To bring Rudolf here? -Yes, yes, to bring him here.
但不是单方面的 你懂吗
But it doesn't happen unilaterally, do you understand?
要进行一次交换
It has to be an exchange.
妈妈，他不在这
Mama, er ist nicht da.
不在吗
Not here?
喔妈妈
Oh mein Mama.
没关系的
Es ist ja okay.
嘘
Shh.
冷静一下
Ruh dich aus
嘘 嘘
Shh. Shh.
他会回来的
Er kommt doch zurück.
是多诺万先生吗
Mr. Donovan?
沃格尔先生
Mr. Vogel.
不不不 天呐
No, no, no. Goodness.
我的名字叫希什金 伊万 希什金
My name is Schischkin. Ivan Schischkin.
我是苏联大使馆的二等秘书
I'm the second secretary of the Soviet embassy.
沃格尔先生的加入不太合适
It wouldn't be appropriate for Mr. Vogel to join us.
因为他是德国公民
He is a German national.
所以你不是来
So you aren't here to...
我是来促成这次会面的
To facilitate this meeting.
或许 阿贝尔太太
Uh, perhaps Mrs. Abel
可以自己先平静下来吗
would like to compose herself privately?
让我可以和多诺万先生谈谈
And let Mr. Donovan and myself to talk?
谢谢
Thank you.
－我有点不太明白 －怎么了
-So, I'm confused. -Yes.
我不在乎和我谈话的人是谁
Uh, I don't care who I talk to
只要可以谈谈人员交换的事
if it's about an exchange of personnel.
你是我可以交谈的人吗
Are you the person to talk to?
是是是 当然 我们应该谈谈
Yes, yes, yes, of course. Uh, we should talk.
请坐 多诺万先生
Please, have a seat, Mr. Donovan.
你是怎么来东区的呢
Uh, how did you arrive to the Eastern sector?
乘火车来的 城铁
The train. The S-Bahn.
啊 你是一个人吗
Ah, and you were alone?
是的
Yeah.
所以你有证件吗
And you are credentialed?
现在 先生 你必须要了解一下我
Now, you must know about me, sir.
我是一位普通公民
I'm a private citizen.
我是来自美国布鲁克林的一名律师
I'm a lawyer in Brooklyn in the United States,
我从繁忙的日程中抽身
and I've taken time out of my busy schedule
帮助我的当事人 鲁道夫·阿贝尔
to help my client, Rudolf Abel.
我被授予权力安排阿贝尔
I'm authorized to arrange an exchange of Abel
和弗朗西斯·加里·鲍尔斯进行交换
for Francis Gary Powers.
交换一旦成功
This is a full pardon of Abel
阿贝尔的赦免文件将立即签署
that will be signed when the exchange actually takes place.
这是我来这儿的唯一理由
This is the only reason I'm here.
我希望并期待这项安排快速进行
I hope and expect to make this arrangement quickly.
阿贝尔换弗朗西斯·加里·鲍尔斯
Abel for Francis Gary Powers
以及弗雷德里克·普莱尔
and Frederic Pryor.
嗯哼 普莱尔不在我们手里
Mmm, we don't have Pryor.
不在 不会吧
No? You don't?
我听说过普莱尔 但是他在
I've heard of Pryor, but he's held
德意志民主共和国手里
by the German Democratic Republic,
而不在苏维埃社会主义共和国联邦手里
not by the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics.
好吧 我要告诉你我的第一个问题
Well, I'll tell you the first problem.
你们国家的名字太长了
The names of your countries are too long.
是的 的确
Yes, yes.
如果我们释放了鲍尔斯
If we release Powers,
全是为了促进我们两国之间的
it is only to promote a goodwill
友好往来
between our countries.
所以 不应该是一场交易
So, it cannot be an exchange.
或许
Perhaps...
或许你们可以放了阿贝尔
Perhaps you could release Abel
作为一个友好的象征
as a token of goodwill to our friends in Germany,
接下来 几个月之后
and then, some months later,
我们就会放了鲍尔斯
we would release Powers.
－这是一个主意 －不 那样对我们没有利
-There is an idea. -No. That just won't work for us at all.
听着 我们以交易的方式进行
See, we need this to be an exchange.
你可以随便称之为什么
You can call it what you want,
但它必须是一场交易
but an exchange it must be.
我们可以保证阿贝尔48小时之内回到俄国
We can have Abel here within 48 hours.
但与此同时 鲍尔斯也要返回美国
We need Powers at the same time we give you Abel.
这是
Hmm. This is...
我可以称之为 急躁的计划 吗
Can we call this the "impatient plan"?
喔 你可以随便怎么叫它
Well, you can call it whatever you want.
我可以将你这项急躁的计划传达到莫斯科
I can relay your impatient plan to Moscow,
看看他们怎么说
see what they say...
但是他们会想知道为什么如此急躁
But they will wonder why so impatient.
因为我感冒了
Because I have a cold.
而且我不住在柏林 我想回家
And I don't live in Berlin and I want to go home.
他们会认为
They will think,
噢 美国人肯定已经得到了
"Well, the Americans must have gotten
阿贝尔已知的全部机密
"all the information that Abel had to give.
所以他们现在急着要用他来做交易
"And now they're impatient to trade him,
希望把鲍尔斯换走
"hoping to get in return this man, Powers,
或许 鲍尔斯还没有说出
"that, perhaps, has not yet given up
他所获取的全部机密
"all the information that he has to give."
这是一场不公平的交易 先生
This is not an equitable trade, sir.
那么你的意思是
But what you're saying is,
如果鲍尔斯将他所知道的全盘托出
if Powers has given up everything he knows,
莫斯科方面就会同意这场交易吗
then Moscow would trade?
为什么不呢
Why wouldn't they?
至于阿贝尔 如果他死在了美国的监狱中
As for Abel, if he dies in an American prison,
下一个被捕的俄国特工
the next Russian operative who gets caught
可能会考虑松个口
might think twice about keeping his mouth shut.
谁知道呢 阿贝尔他本人可能想再次见到天空
And you never know. Abel might want to see the sky again
然后就决定用俄国机密来帮美国一点小忙
and decide to trade Russian secrets for small American favors.
那我们怎么知道呢
How can we know this?
我们这些小人物 只是完成自己的工作
We little men, we just do our jobs.
比如鲍尔斯中尉 他只是一名飞行员
Like Lieutenant Powers. He's just a pilot.
当他在空中被射中的时候
He was making photographs from 70,000 feet
他正在从7万英尺的高空拍照
when he was shot from the sky.
我国民众认为
People in my country consider this
这就是一次战争挑衅
an act of war.
我们没有必要再说这件事 先生
We have to get off this merry-go-round, sir.
我们国家下一次犯错
The next mistake our countries make
有可能就是最后一次
could be the last one.
我们有必要进行这次谈话
We need to have the conversation
这是我们双方政府所不能的
our governments can't.
我会询问莫斯科方面
I will ask Moscow.
谁知道他们的态度是什么呢
Who knows what they will say.
多诺万先生 有很多人
There are a lot of people, Mr. Donovan,
都不希望这场交易发生
who doesn't want this exchange to ever take place.
你可以明天再来吗 到时候讨论他们给出的答案
Can you come back tomorrow to discuss their answer?
用阿贝尔换鲍尔斯
Powers for Abel.
以及弗雷德里克·普莱尔
And Frederic Pryor.
我前面说过了
As I said,
普莱尔现在在
Pryor is in the hands of the organs of
德意志民主共和国 国家安全机关手里
State Security of the German Democratic Republic.
我相信你可以安排
I'm confident you can make arrangements.
我只是一个秘书
I am merely a secretary
身在外国的大使馆
in the embassy of foreign power.
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay.
你必须要见见沃格尔先生 我会给你他的地址
You have to see Mr. Vogel. I'll give you his address.
真的有一位沃格尔先生
There actually is a Mr. Vogel?
不然你以为呢
Why would you imagine otherwise?
要坐一趟短途出租车
Uh, it's a short cab ride.
多诺万先生 请你
And please, Mr. Donovan,
在这样的天气里最好穿一件大衣
wear an overcoat in this weather.
我的被偷了
I had mine stolen from me.
你还希望他们还回来吗
What do you expect?
是在萨克斯第五大道被偷的
It was from Saks Fifth Avenue.
是不是
Wasn't it?
多诺万先生
Mr. Donovan.
沃格尔先生
Mr. Vogel.
请进
Please come in.
多谢
Danke.
大使馆的事很抱歉
Sorry about the embassy.
但是是苏联决定不让我去
But the Soviets decided not to host me.
实在是气人
Very irritating.
我现在仍在努力获取每个党派的
I am still trying to grasp each party's...
地位情况
Status?
是的 以及在这场诉讼中的利益
Yes. And interest in the proceedings.
喔
Oh.
真是一个新世界
It's a new world.
一切都乱了套 对吧
All very disorienting, isn't it?
我来告诉你我的建议是什么
Let me tell you what I have to offer.
我的好朋友
I'm a good friend...
朋友 不 他已经年老了
"Friend." No, he's older.
盟友 吗
"Protege"?
是德意志民主共和国的首席检查官
Of the attorney general of the German Democratic Republic.
请坐
Sit down, please.
这位不幸的
This unfortunate,
弗雷德里克·普莱尔
Frederic Pryor,
他在错误的时间呆在了错误的地点
he was in the wrong place at the wrong time.
每个意外 如果正确解读的话
But every accident, properly viewed,
也是一个机会 不是吗 多诺万先生
is an opportunity, isn't it, Mr. Donovan?
嗯哼 你的国家拒绝承认
Well... Your country refuses to recognize
德意志民主共和国
the German Democratic Republic.
他们更喜欢编造故事
They prefer to make up stories
比如 他们说德意志民主共和国这个国家不存在
that the GDR doesn't exist, for instance.
不好意思
Sorry.
先生 要让你的政府承认
As a means of forcing your government's recognition
这个真实存在的地方
of this real place, sir,
其中一个方式就是 你自己去发现
in which you find yourself,
德意志民主共和国
the GDR,
首席检查官很开心可以和你协商
the attorney general is happy to negotiate with you
你作为政府代表
as a representative of your government
欢迎普莱尔回国
for Mr. Pryor's return.
沃格尔先生 我来这儿
Mr. Vogel, I'm not here
不代表我国政府
as a representative of my government.
好吧
All right.
多诺万先生 我认为这样很幼稚
I think that's childish, Mr. Donovan.
我 我没有官方身份
Well, I... I have no official status.
很好
Fine.
你不代表美国 我也不代表东德
You do not represent the USA, I do not represent the GDR.
我的当事人是莉迪亚·阿贝尔 鲁道夫的妻子
My client is Lydia Abel, Rudolf's wife.
而且我
And I have also...
莉迪亚是女儿 海伦才是妻子
Lydia is the daughter. Helen is the wife.
哇哦
Well...
我准备
I am prepared to offer
用弗雷德里克·普莱尔来交换鲁道夫·阿贝尔
Frederic Pryor's exchange for Rudolf Abel's.
现在让我们来理理清楚
Then let's be clear.
我们会释放鲁道夫·阿贝尔
We will produce Rudolf Abel.
同时 你们也要释放学生普莱尔
You will produce, at the same time, the student, Pryor.
同时
At the same time?
当然
Absolutely.
交易就是用一个暮年的俄国人
The exchange on offer is a Russian at the end of his life
来交换一个正值青春的美国学生
for an American student at the start of his.
希什金 他不是大使馆秘书
Schischkin? He's not an embassy secretary.
伊万·希什金是苏联驻西欧国家安全委员会的长官
Ivan Schischkin is the KGB's chief in western Europe.
好吧 不管他是谁
Well, whatever he is,
他会把我们的提议传达到莫斯科
he's relaying our proposal to Moscow
然后作出决定
and they'll decide.
可以借我一件大衣吗 我的丢了
Could I borrow a coat? I lost mine.
你怎么会把你的大衣丢了
How did you lose your coat?
你知道的 间谍人员
You know, spy stuff.
－我会给你再找一件大衣 －很好 因为
-I'll get you another coat. -Good, because...
那...这个叫沃格尔的人是谁
So who is, uh... Who is this Vogel?
他 不知道
Him, we don't know.
你说他是谁 他就是谁
He might be what you said he said he is.
首席检查官的朋友
Friend of the attorney general.
只是一个东德派来处理这件事的人
Just some guy the GDR tapped to handle this.
听起来像是东德
Sounds like the East Germans
在我们的势力范围争夺地盘
are fighting for a place at our table.
东德为俄国人换回阿贝尔
The GDR gets Abel back for the Russians,
同时赢得尊敬
winning their respect...
然后为自己的事业作出贡献
And capturing the headlines for their cause.
这个贡献当然就是 把东德放到地图上
Which, of course, puts East Germany on the map.
但是 我们不在乎他们的地图
But we don't care about their map.
继续和俄国人周旋
Stick with the Russians.
继续和俄国人周旋 用阿贝尔换回鲍尔斯
Stick with the Russians. It's Powers for Abel.
那么 这一切都意味着这有可能发生吗
So, does all this mean this might actually happen?
是 似乎这是你所告诉我的
Yeah, that's what you seem to be telling me.
我们会把阿贝尔放上飞机 在周五到达
We'll put Abel on a plane, he'll be here Friday.
因此 如果希什金得到肯定答复
So, if Schischkin gets the okay,
然后剩下的就全是交易的技巧了
all that's left is the mechanics of the trade.
如何用我们的人换他们的人
How we swap our guy for their guy.
我们的人们 两个人
Our "guys." Two guys.
鲍尔斯和普莱尔
Powers and Pryor.
不 现在 不要跟我搞什么软心肠
No, now don't go bleeding heart on me.
鲍尔斯才是关键
Powers is the whole ball game.
忘掉这个常春藤的学生
Forget this Ivy League boy,
他显然认为到柏林学习苏联经济学
who obviously thought it was a good idea
是个好主意
to study Soviet economics in Berlin
在这样一个冷战时期
in the middle of the Cold War.
鲍尔斯才是我们要的人
Powers is who we need.
你根本不喜欢鲍尔斯
You don't even like Powers.
没有人喜欢鲍尔斯
Everybody hates Powers.
他没有自杀 还允许共产党把他放在电视上示威
He didn't kill himself and he let the commies parade him on television.
他现在是美国最讨厌的人
He's the most hated man in America.
有可能 仅次于鲁道夫·阿贝尔
After Rudolf Abel, maybe.
和我
And me.
醒醒
Now wake up!
我要睡觉
I gotta sleep.
我只想睡觉
I just gotta sleep.
我告诉你 你可以睡
I told you, you can sleep
但只要我们想谈话的时候 就必须要谈话
once we talk what we need to talk.
你要听命于我
You must focus on me.
你的政府根本不在意你 你知道的
Your government doesn't care about you. You know that.
不在意你们任何一个人
Any of you.
你知道那12名U-2飞行员脑损伤的事吗
You know that twelve U-2 pilots incurred brain damage?
由于高海拔缺氧 他们现在变成了植物人
They're vegetables because of altitude, insufficient oxygen.
但是加里 他们还让你飞行
But they keep you flying, Gary.
你和你的朋友
You and your friends.
他们还给了你这个 一个划皮利器 是吧
They gave you this. A scratcher, yes?
上面涂的是氰化钾
Potassium cyanide.
这看起来像是他们在意你们吗
Does that look like they care about you?
爆炸装置的结构是什么
What is the construction of the destructor unit?
怎样才可以操作
By what means is this unit operated?
这个带电装置用的是什么炸药
With what explosives is the unit charged,
它的毁灭能力有多大
and what destruction is it capable of?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们不会向飞行员展示任何设备
The pilots were never shown any of the equipment.
飞机过境期间
How wide far can the radar
雷达可以测到地图上多远的距离
map an area during an overflight?
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know, I don't know!
那你是不是在4月9号的时候
Were you making the overflight on April 9th
在巴拉诺维奇的工业区和米格轰炸基地上空
over the industrial area and MiG bomber base
飞越过境
at Baranovichi?
我没有
I was not.
这次是我第一次过境飞行
This was my first overflight.
我要知道发动机熄火到滑翔期间的比率
I need to know about engine-out to glide ratio.
飞机怎么可以飞那么高
How the plane gets so high.
我们知道它飞到了7万英尺
We know it reaches altitude of 70,000 feet.
加里 我们都知道
Gary, we know this.
现在我要你告诉我飞机都飞过哪些区域
And I need to know where the planes have flown.
加里 他们都飞过哪里
Where they have flown, Gary.
现在 我们必须要谈谈了
And we must have this talk now.
就现在
Now.
然后你就可以小睡一会
And then you can sleep a little.
先生 醒醒
Sir, wake up.
起来了 先生
Wake up, sir.
先生 请跟我走 可以吗 好
Sir, can you come with me, please? Yeah.
我们得走了 好的 没问题
We gotta move. Yeah, of course.
跟我走 可以吗 好的
Can you come with me, please? Yeah.
没问题
Okay.
－眼镜拿了吗 －嗯哼
-Got your glasses? -Uh-huh.
－现在几点了 －很晚了 但是我们得谈谈
-What time is it? -It's late, but we need to talk,
然后 我们还要去赶飞机 成吗
and then we need to get on a plane, okay?
好 好的 起了起了
Yeah. Yep. Upsy-daisy!
－起了起了 －这才对
-Upsy-daisy. -That's right.
这边走 不要停
There we go. Keep it moving.
谢谢
Thank you.
另一边 另一边
Other way, other way.
这才对
There we go.
你刚刚说飞机
You say a plane?
这边 请 继续走
This way, please. Keep moving.
所以 针对你的提议
So, I received a favorable decision
莫斯科方面给出了相当令人满意的答复
from Moscow on your proposal
我们愿意帮助我们德国民主共和国的朋友
that we help our friends in the German Democratic Republic
用鲍尔斯先生来交换
by exchanging
阿贝尔先生
Mr. Powers for Mr. Abel.
那可太好了
That's swell.
把格林尼克桥作为互换地点地点怎么样
May I suggest the Glienicke Bridge as a place of a swap?
为什么不在查理检查站
Why not Checkpoint Charlie?
我们不想引起公众的注意
We're not looking for publicity.
格林尼克桥非常人际悄然
The Glienicke Bridge is very quiet,
尤其是清晨的时候
especially early in the morning.
格林尼克桥 我会和我们那边的人核对一下
Glienicke Bridge. I'll run that by our side.
阿贝尔周五就能到这里
We can have Abel here on Friday.
所以 周六早晨怎么样
So, Saturday morning?
总是这么心急 是吧
Always impatience, yeah?
我就想早点回家睡一觉
I want to get home and get into bed.
那就 周六早晨
So, Saturday morning?
5:30
5:30?
没问题
All right.
总算谈妥了
We're done here.
这是我们的电话
This is a number,
有什么意外的话拨这个号码
in case anything should come up.
好
All right.
不论何时都会有人接听
Someone will answer at any hour.
我希望我用不着它
I don't expect to use it.
我们要不要庆祝一下
Shall we toast the arrangement?
何不呢
Why not?
亚美尼亚白兰地
Armenian brandy.
－对你的感冒有好处 －谢谢
-Good bracer for your cold. -Thank you.
你介不介意
Would you mind...
这不是我们工作中的一部分
This is not part of our business
但是 我想问你几个问题
but I'd like to ask you a couple of questions.
你不一定非得回答我
You do not have to answer.
尽我所能
I shall answer what I know.
我挺喜欢他的 你们的人
I like this guy, your guy.
他回去了之后会怎样
What happens to your guy when he gets home?
这个 我们需要进行一场审查
Well, we have to make a determination
看看他是不是已经成为你们的人了
whether our guy is now your guy.
这 如我之前所说
Now, as I said to you before,
他不辱使命
he's acted honorably.
他还是站在你们的阵线上的 相信我
He's still your guy, believe me.
你当然会这么说
Of course you will say that if it were true
不管是真是假
and if it were not true.
我猜只能这样了是吧
I guess it has come down to that, huh?
那个 原谅我这么多问题
Well, forgive me for pushing,
但是 他会有危险吗
but is he in any danger
如果审查下来之后
if the determination is made?
这个 天哪
Well, goodness.
就现在的状况来看 每个人都身处危险之中
As things are now, everyone is in danger.
干杯
Cheers.
祝健康
Na zdorovie.
格林尼克桥上不会有什么交换
There will be no exchange on Glienicke Bridge.
你说什么 先生
Excuse me, sir.
不会有交换
There will be no exchange.
不会交换弗雷德里克·普莱尔
Not for Frederic Pryor.
沃格尔先生 我以为昨天我们都谈妥了
Mr. Vogel, I thought yesterday we had agreed.
我们是谈好了 条件是 用阿贝尔换普莱尔
We agreed on an exchange, Abel for Pryor.
现在我才知道 原来你是个奸商
Now I learn you are a rug merchant
把同一件商品卖给两个人
selling the same rug to two customers.
－我们这边 你说用阿贝尔换普莱尔 －对啊
-Abel for Pryor you sell to us. -Yeah.
苏联那边 你又说用阿贝尔换鲍尔斯
And Abel for Powers you sell to the Soviets.
我不太清楚 这笔交易
I'm not quite sure what the problem is
可以让多方满意 有什么问题吗
if the arrangement satisfies two parties or three or four.
有什么区别呢
What difference does it make?
这笔交易不能让我方感到满意
The arrangement does not satisfy this party.
这样 沃格尔先生 请您
Now, Mr. Vogel, please...
很明显 你不清楚你在和什么人打交道
Obviously you do not know who you are dealing with.
我们现在的谈判关乎着德国民主共和国的
Here's the interest of the German Democratic Republic.
利益所在
To deal with,
而谈判的另一方 是另一个拥有主权的国家
and to be seen to be dealing with another sovereign power,
美国
the United States.
等同的权利
An equal power.
而你对待我们
Instead you treat us as stooges
就像对待苏维埃社会主义共和国的傀儡一样
for the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics.
我们能直接说 俄国吗 这样比较省时间
Can we just call them the Russians? It'll save time.
我还有其他事情 先生
I have an appointment, sir.
在我看来 是你在浪费时间
I think it's you who are wasting time.
这样吧 你看我说的对不对
Now, tell me if I am describing this wrong.
那个孩子在你们手上 一个普通大学生
You have a kid, a university student,
据你们所知 不是什么间谍
someone you know is not a spy,
对你们毫无威胁
who's no threat to you.
而用来交换的这个人
And in exchange for this person
同样对你们毫无利用价值可言
who is worthless to you,
在这场交易中 不论是对俄国还是美国而言
you play an equal part in an exchange
你们始终都处于平等地位
between the Russians and the Americans.
这只不过是我们和你们双方进行了一场交换
And this is one transaction between us and the two of you.
这不是两件独立的事件 先生
We're not trying to do two things here, sir.
这始终都只是一件事啊 仅此一件
We're just doing one thing. One, one, one.
我也不愿意看到东德民主共和国被轻视
It's hard for me to see how the Republic of East German Democrats is being slighted.
你没有和我商量就和苏联谈妥了条件
You agreed with the Soviets without consulting me.
这算是谈判吗 这算合谋吧
Is this a negotiation or a conspiracy?
如果是合谋的话
For it to be a conspiracy,
那应该是对您有害的交易啊 先生
there would have to be harm to you, sir.
但是这场交易有益无害 我们有着共同的利益
There's just benefits here. We're of agreeing interests.
不 是你觉得有共同利益
No, you decide they agree.
您要去哪赴会 先生
Where is your appointment, sir?
去西边 库丹大道
In the West. Ku'damm.
正好
Good.
你看周围
Look around you.
东德和西德比起来怎么样 嗯
How does the Eastern sector compare with the West? Hmm?
我们的俄国朋友建议我们
Our Russian friends have decided that
我们没有必要重建首都
we should not rebuild our capital city.
但是我们却生活在我们俄国朋友造成的废墟之中
But we live in this ruin made by our Russian friends.
去吧 和俄国人完成你们的交易吧
Go ahead, make your deal with these Russians.
我们可不掺和
We won't be part of it.
没有普莱尔的话就没有什么交易
There is no deal without Pryor.
我们不会把他扔在这不管
We are not leaving him here.
这是你的立场还是你们政府的立场
Is this your position or your government's?
先生 是我在这 和您谈条件
Sir, I'm here. I'm talking to you.
但是你却不代表你的政府
But you are not a representative of your government.
你已经不知道你是谁了 我们也不知道
You don't know who you are. Neither do we.
你需要小心 这儿可不是布鲁克林 多诺万先生
You should be careful. This is not Brooklyn, Mr. Donovan.
这样说吧 先生
Look, sir.
您想必知道不论何种情况下
You must know that in every respect that matters,
我都代表这我的政府
I represent my government.
您很清楚我是谁
You know who I am.
是吗
Do I?
啊哦
Uh-oh.
你有身份证明吗
Do you have the proper papers?
当然没有 无所谓了
Of course not. It doesn't matter.
一个像你这样的美国律师
An American lawyer like you
不管什么罪名都能开脱的了
can talk your way out of anything.
不是吗
Can't you?
你很快就可以继续上路了
Dann bald bist du schnell unterwegs.
是啊没错
Ja, dann mich vollkomm Recht
你的证件 快
Ihren Ausweis, schnell!
他不会德语
Er spricht kein deutsch.
来自美国的同事
Kollege aus Amerika.
也是律师
auch Rechtsanwalt.
美国人
Amerikaner.
你 下车
Du, aussteigen!
下车
los!
沃格尔先生 祝您接下来的旅途愉快
Herr Vogel, ich wünsche Ihnen eine gute Weiterfahrt.
谢谢
Danke.
你跟他走
You go with him.
－为什么 －护照问题
-Why? -It's passport problem.
什么 什么问题 究竟有什么问题
What... What problem? What's the problem?
你跟他走
You go with him.
记住了
And remember,
弗雷德里克·普莱尔的命运掌控在我们手中
we control the fate of Frederic Pryor.
站起来
Aufstehen
跟我走
Mitkommen.
嗯 先给我上杯咖啡 谢谢
Yeah, I'll start with some coffee, please.
然后 我要一份希尔顿套餐
Then I'll have the Hilton combo
和美式早餐
and the American breakfast.
还有咖啡
And coffee.
两份早餐
Both breakfasts?
对的
Yeah, yeah.
先上一份还是
One first or...
都上 一起上 做好了就上
Both first, both. Whenever they're ready.
－还有咖啡 －嗯
-And coffee. -Hmm.
你不应该来这
You shouldn't be here.
嗯 在德国的时候吧
Well, sometimes in Germany,
有的时候就是想要来一顿丰盛的美式早餐
you just want a big American breakfast.
发生了什么 昨晚你去哪了
What happened? Where were you last night?
沃格尔安排我在东德过了个夜
Vogel arranged for me to spend some time in the East.
哦 天啊
Oh, Jesus.
坦白的说 还不算是特别糟
Frankly, it's not that much worse
没有比你给我安排的在西德住的地方更糟
than where you have me here in the West.
俄国方面同意交换了
So the Russians are fine with the exchange,
但是沃格尔说 东德方面不同意放人
but now Vogel is saying that the East Germans won't do it.
我们换不来普莱尔
We're not gonna get Pryor.
太棒了 太好了
Great, good.
所以苏联同意了 我们能够换回鲍尔斯
So the Soviets are set. We get Powers.
我们能换回鲍尔斯
We get Powers.
干得漂亮
Well done.
但是 东德不同意换人
No, the East Germans won't do it.
我们换不回普莱尔 那个孩子也很重要
We won't get Pryor, and that kid matters.
每个人都很重要
Every person matters.
当然 所以你才费尽心思嘛 你都费劲心思了
Sure, that's why you tried. That's why you tried.
阿贝尔已经在来的路上了 所以 我们就等明天早上了
Abel's on his way, so we're all set for tomorrow morning.
－你等等 －别搞那么复杂 别把事情搞复杂了
-Wait a minute. -Makes things simple. Makes things simple.
我们救不回那个孩子
We are not getting the kid.
是是 我知道 万事俱备了已经
Yeah, I understand. We're set.
今天早上得到的消息无关紧要了
We can ignore the message we got this morning.
什么消息
What message?
东德那边的消息
From the East Germans.
他们打到了我给你的那个号码
They called the number I gave you.
他们说 他们今天想和你谈谈
They said they wanted to speak to you today.
－沃格尔打来的 －不是 嗯
-Vogel called? -No, um...
嗯 哈拉尔德·奥特 从
Office of, uh, Harald Ott,
东德检察长办公室打来的
East German attorney general.
干吗 他想干嘛
Wanting what? What does he want?
额 想跟你谈谈
Well, to talk to you.
但是无所谓 我不会要求你再回到那边去
But it's okay, I can't ask you to go back there.
而且听着 你看起来似乎有点 不太受人欢迎
And listen, you seem to be persona non grata to some elements,
所以 我们就别冒这个险了
so we won't push our luck.
所以他想见我
So he wants to see me.
什么时候
What time?
啊 不 别别 你听着
Oh, no, no. Now, listen.
你不一定非得去 实际上 你不应该去
You don't need to go. In fact, you shouldn't go.
事实是 你不能去
In fact, you can't go.
我们好不容易和苏联谈妥了 我们可不想搞砸了
We're set with the Soviets. We don't want to screw it up.
－我不会搞砸的 －你不能去
-I'm not gonna screw it up. -You're not going!
别总这么招人烦行吗
Don't be a pain in the ass.
啊 我点的
Oh, I ordered.
好好享受你的美式早餐吧
Enjoy your big American breakfast.
我想由我们这个最高领导层和您谈判
I thought it should be negotiated
应该比较符合礼节
at the highest level as a courtesy to you.
非常感谢 先生
I thank you, sir.
我不明白事情为什么变得 这么混沌不清
I don't know how things became so confused.
这个 我猜或许它们本该如此吧
Well, I guess sometimes they just do.
我就直说了
For sake of clarity,
我们已经准备好进行交换了
I say we are fully prepared to exchange
用那个叫什么普莱尔的学生来换鲁道夫·阿贝尔
the so-called student, Pryor, for Rudolf Abel.
我从沃格尔先生那里得知了普莱尔对你来说非常重要
I understand from Mr. Vogel that Pryor is very important to you.
是的 但是
Yes, but...
我们会为你此番辛劳做下备忘录的
Ah, we'll do a memorandum to that effect.
啊 备忘录啊
Oh, a memorandum.
很显然 我们将要进行一场双面交易
Certainly, we commit to a bi-lateral exchange.
是是是 虽然我不太清楚那是什么意思 但是
Yes, yes, sure. I'm not sure what that means but...
我国也坚持能够换回弗朗西斯·加里·鲍尔斯
My country also insists on Francis Gary Powers.
没门
No!
对不起
Entschuldigen Sie!
这就是为什么事情变得如此的混沌不清
This is how things became so confused.
鲍尔斯 要他干嘛呢 先生
Powers. What use is he, sir?
你们想要把他换回去然后惩罚他吗
You want him back for punitive reasons?
木已成舟
What's done is done.
他该交代的他都交代的差不多了
He has divulged what he will divulge,
想必阿贝尔也一样
as no doubt Abel has also.
我们同意将清白无辜的平民百姓交还给你们
We are offering instead someone who you insist is innocent.
这才是对的
And this is right.
这才是你应该争取的
This is who you should retrieve.
远见
The future.
要有远见啊
Look to the future.
奥特
Ott.
我干嘛要关心这个
Wieso soll ich mich darum kümmern?
这应该叫做什么？
Was soll es heißen?die Bezügsleitung?
他在哪
Wo ist er?
好，那你跟同事说一下我马上过去
Ja, dann sagen den Genossen, dass ich gleich vorbei
不好意思 你能等我一会吗 先生
I'm sorry. If you could give me a moment, sir.
不好意思 先生 检察长非常抱歉
I'm very sorry, sir. The attorney general regrets
他必须去处理一项紧急事务
that he had to leave on urgent business.
－他走了 －是的 非常抱歉
-He left? -Yes. Many apologies.
我都等了一个多小时了
I've been waiting for over an hour.
深感抱歉 先生
Very sorry, sir.
年轻人
Young man.
你来
Come here.
没事 来吧
It's all right. Come here.
额 请坐
Uh... Take a seat.
哦 没事的 快来 坐下
Oh, come on, come on. Sit down.
你喜欢你的工作吗
Do you like your job here?
这是一份相当好的工作
It's a very good job, sir.
那必须 一定很有趣吧
It must be. Must be interesting.
嗯 是的 先生
Oh, yes, sir.
同样也很重要
And important, too.
你的英语相当 相当不错
And your English is... Is good.
是的 虽然我不太敢说很棒
Yes, I hesitate to say it's excellent.
但是 其实我的英语很棒的 先生
But it's excellent, sir.
好好  非常好
Good, good. Good.
你看 我的谈判对象已经走了
See, I just lost my negotiating partner,
我需要想找人谈一下
and I need somebody to talk to,
你看起来 是个通情达理的年轻人
and you seem like a reasonable young man.
我能跟你聊聊吧
Can I talk to you?
额
Uh...
没关系
It's all right.
不要紧的 我只是
It's all right. I just...
我只是想让你帮我带个口信给你的上司
I just need you to give a message to your boss.
但是 这个口信必须要准确无误地带到
But it has to be very, very, very clear.
你明白吗
You understand?
是 先生 但是 也许你应该等他
Yes, sir. But perhaps you should wait until he...
不 不 关键是 我感冒了 我只想早点回家
No, no. The thing is, I have this cold and I wanna get home
好好睡一觉
and get in bed.
你能帮我带这个口信吗
Can you give him the message?
没问题
Certainly.
好的 你就这么说
Well, this is the message.
如果不能同时交换鲍尔斯和普莱尔的话 我们也不会交出阿贝尔
"There is no deal for Abel unless we get Powers and Pryor."
－你清楚了吧 －是的 先生
-Do you understand? -Yes, sir.
本来安排的是明早
It's arranged for tomorrow morning.
但是 少一个就没得谈
It will not happen unless we get two men.
两个人
Those two men.
－缺一不可 －明白 先生
-Two, two, two. -Yes, sir.
如果交易没能成功
If there is no deal,
你的上司就得告诉苏联那边
your boss must tell the Soviets.
他就得给苏联说
He has to tell the Soviets
他们不能换回鲁道夫·阿贝尔
that they are not getting Rudolf Abel.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
哦 还有 告诉他
Oh, and tell him this.
目前为止 阿贝尔都恪守军人职责
That so far, Abel has been a good soldier,
那是因为他知道他就快回家了
but he thinks he's going home.
如果我们不得不告诉他他回不去了
If we had to tell him that he's not going home,
因为苏联抛弃了他
that the Soviets don't even want him,
他永远都不可能回家了
that he's never going home...
这样 我想他的口风估计就不会那么严了吧
Well, I imagine his behavior might change.
这样的话有什么后果谁来负责呢
And who will be held responsible for that?
这个口信够长的
That's a long message.
额 你都记下了吗
Uh, did you get it all?
－是的 先生 记住了 －非常好
-Yes, sir. Got it. -Good.
你是个好小伙
You're a good man.
对了
Oh...
再告诉他
And also tell him
如果今天下班之前得不到回复的话
there's no deal unless we hear
交易也会取消
before the end of business today.
他有我的电话
He has the number.
如果交易取消的话
If the exchange isn't gonna happen,
那我们大家都不用起个大早了
no reason for everybody to get up first thing in the morning.
是的 先生 没有必要了
No, sir, that would be pointless.
你逗我呢 你逗我玩呢
You're kidding me! You're kidding me!
并不算 给我点零钱
Not really. I need some change.
这完全是你份外的事
This is exactly what you weren't supposed to do.
我的指令让我随机应变
My instructions were to feel out the situation.
你的指令让你带回鲍尔斯就行 不是普莱尔
Your instructions were to get Powers, not Pryor.
那可不是你此行的目的 你全搞砸了
That was not the original deal. You fouled it all up!
你怎么知道 我感觉还成
How do you know? I feel pretty good about it.
你全搞砸了
You fucked it all up!
哦 别着急
Oh, don't worry.
我觉得 会有个好结果的
I think it's gonna be fine.
你怎么知道 你怎么敢那么肯定
How do you know? You don't know that.
请接弗兰克 斯普莱
Frank Spread, bitte.
美国 纽约州 纽约市
United States. New York, New York.
谢谢
Danke.
这么说吧 这整件事
Look, this whole thing
就是为了试探我的底线
has been to feel me out.
我会同意以一换一吗 换哪个
Would I swap one for one and which one?
但是我拒绝了 我说 不行 两个换一个
But I said "No, two for one."
这下他们就知道我们的立场了
So they know where we stand.
好吧 那如果他们考虑之后 答复说
Yeah, what if they think about it and say, uh...
算了吧 你留着我们那一个人吧 我们这有你两个人
"Forget it! You keep our guy, we keep your guys"?
这样的话 我才算是真的搞砸了
Well, then I have fucked it all up.
嘿 宝贝 是我
Hey, honey! It's me.
是的 钓鱼之行相当不错
Yeah. The fishing's been great.
我在伦敦
I'm in London,
再有一个会 我就回家了
just for one more meeting, then I'm on my way home.
对 对 我记得那个果酱
Yeah, yeah, I remember that marmalade.
摄政公园旁边的那个店是吧
It's that shop right by Regent's Park.
好的 我会的 如果我抽得出空的话
All right, I will if I have the time.
嘿 我能和罗杰打个招呼嘛
Hey, can I say hi to Roger?
那我能跟姑娘们打个招呼嘛
Could I say hi to the girls?
有谁是不忙的吗
Is anyone not busy?
他们注意到我好几天不在家了吗
Have they even noticed I'm not around?
成了
We're on.
两个换一个
Two for one.
太棒了
Hot dog.
让我们干一杯
Let's have a drink.
－但是有个条件 －什么
-One wrinkle. -What is that?
普莱尔不会和鲍尔斯一起在桥上进行交换
They won't release Pryor with Powers, not at the bridge.
但是 他们会同时释放他
They'll release him at the same time.
俄国人在桥上把鲍尔斯交给我们的同时
When the Russians give us Powers on the bridge,
他们就在查理检查站那里放了普莱尔
they'll release Pryor over Checkpoint Charlie.
他们什么意思
What does that mean?
我觉得他们是想 最后做些挣扎吧
I think it means, "We wanna have the last word."
好歹他们同意了
But they will do it.
这得你说了 你都试探清楚他们的底细了
You tell me. You felt them out.
他们人呢
Where are they?
我们的人呢 我们的人呢
Where's our guy? Where's our guy?
他们迟到了
They're late.
没人迟到 是我们早到了
Nobody's late. We're early.
－能让我用用吗 －给
-May I? -Yeah.
霍夫曼
Hoffman.
怎么了
Yeah?
我觉得他们那边
I think they have...
什么
What?
有狙击手
...snipers.
哦 那肯定啊
Well, I'm sure they do.
你为什么肯定
How are you sure they do?
因为我们也安排了狙击手
Because we have snipers.
请下车 先生
Step out, sir.
吉姆
Jim.
亲爱的吉姆
Dear Jim.
你还好吗
How are you?
见到你真高兴
Happy to see you.
这都是你为我安排的吗
Have you arranged all this for me?
这个 看看等会结果怎么样 我再考虑要不要邀功
Well, let's see what this is before I... I take credit for it.
查理检查站那边有普莱尔的消息吗
Any word about Pryor from Checkpoint Charlie?
一点动静没有
Nothing cooking yet.
打扰了 先生
Excuse me, sir.
这是美国空军的乔·墨菲中尉
This is Lieutenant Joe Murphy, United States Air Force,
来帮我们指认鲍尔斯
here to identify Powers.
墨菲中尉 你好
Lieutenant Murphy.
你好 先生
Sir.
有个小问题
There may be a slight glitch.
我离开的时候还风华正茂
I was a young man when I left.
他们该找谁来指认我
Who will they find to identify me?
这个 我希望最好不是你的东德家人
Well, I hope it's not your East German family.
我估计他们连彼此都不一定认得出来
I doubt they could identify each other.
看起来人都到了
Looks like our party.
好了 我们走
Well, let's go.
你可以留在这 多诺万
You can stay here, Donovan.
不可能
Not likely.
开门
Open the gate.
你觉得你回家之后会怎么样
What do you think will happen when you get home?
额 我觉得
Uh, I think...
我会喝杯伏特加
I'll have a vodka.
对啊
Yeah.
没错
但是 鲁道夫 有没有可能会
But, Rudolf, is there not the possibility...
我的人民要枪决我
That my people are going to shoot me?
对
Yes.
－你不担心吗 －有用吗
-You're not worried? -Would it help?
这么给你说吧 朋友
To answer your question, my friend,
我不辱使命 我认为他们知道
I acted honorably. I think they know that.
但是有时候 他们的想法会开小差
But sometimes people think wrong.
凡人就是如此
People are people.
看看他们是如何迎接我的就知道了
Let's see how they greet me.
我该注意什么
What can I look for?
看他们会不会拥抱我还是直接让我上后座
If I'm embraced or just shown the back seat.
是
Da.
帽子脱掉
Take off the hat.
嘿 鲍尔斯
Hey, Powers.
嘿 墨菲
Hey, Murph.
是的 是鲍尔斯
Yeah, that's Powers.
好了 多诺万先生 现在换人吧
All right, Mr. Donovan. We go now!
等一下
Hang on.
相信我 来人的话我肯定会告诉你
Believe me, I will tell you.
这一个人都没有
There's no one here.
他们在查理检查站那边还要释放另一个人
They're releasing another man at Checkpoint Charlie.
我们就是确定一下 他到了没
We're just confirming that he's there.
就现在
Now!
如计划所说 请吧
As per plan, if you please.
我们走
Let's go.
不管普莱尔出不出现 我们都要过去
Pryor will show up or he won't. Let's go.
他们就在等着看 如果普莱尔不出现我们会不会放人
They're waiting to see if we'll do it without him.
我们就站在这 告诉他们 我们不放
We just have to stand here, show them we won't.
我才不管他们想干什么
I don't give a shit what they want.
我们的目的达到了 去吧 阿贝尔
We have our objective. Go ahead, Abel.
走吧 先生 你可以走了
Go ahead, sir. You can go.
如果不能按计划行事 我们就撤了
If it is not to plan, we go home.
要么现在换人 要么我们就走了
We exchange now or we go home!
－你还在等另一个人 －是的
-You're waiting for another man? -Yup.
你也想要换回他
You want him, too.
是的
I want him.
他想要干嘛不重要 先生
Doesn't matter what he wants, sir.
我是管事的 而且你已经自由了
I'm in charge and you are free to go.
请过去吧 到那边去
Please go. Walk across.
我可以等一会
I can wait.
有情况了 还不确定是不是
It's something. I'm not sure yet.
等一下
Hang on!
我们走
Let's go.
接到他了
We got him!
嗯 我 额
Uh, I, uh...
我给你寄了份礼物 吉姆
I sent you a gift, Jim.
是 是一幅画
It's a... It's a painting.
我希望 能对你有所意义
I hope it has some meaning to you.
不好意思 我都没有想着送你点什么
I'm sorry. I didn't think to get you a gift.
这就是你给我的礼物
This is your gift.
回家就是我的礼物
你还好吗
You okay?
走 走 快走
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
多诺万先生
Mr. Donovan.
阿贝尔上校让我把这个给你
Colonel Abel asked me to give this to you.
不好意思 先生
Pardon me, sir.
您是这里的负责人吗 先生
Were you in charge of this thing, sir?
－是 －那我得谢谢您
-Yeah. -Well, I gotta thank you.
我总得谢谢谁
I gotta thank somebody.
我什么都没说 我一个字都没说
I gave them nothing. I gave them nothing.
没关系
It doesn't matter.
别人怎么想无所谓
It doesn't matter what people think.
你心里清楚就好
You know what you did.
欢迎回来
Welcome home.
总算到家了
What a trip.
嗯
Mmm.
你还好吗
You okay?
嗯 挺好的
Yeah, I'm fine.
－果酱你买了吗 －买了买了
-Did you get the marmalade? -Yes, yes.
买了 买了
Yep. Yep.
我买了
I did.
如你所愿
As ordered.
吉姆
Jim.
－这是从阿诺河那边买的 －那又怎样
-This is from Arno's. -So?
－我说的是街角那家 －诶呀宝贝 我很忙嘛
-On the corner!  -Well, honey, I was busy.
－不好意思 我们忙得四脚朝天 －我的天呐
-I'm sorry. We were so busy.  -Oh, for Pete's sake.
－罗杰怎么样 他在家吗 －在家
-How's Roger? Is he home? -He's home.
卡罗尔也在家 佩吉也在家 大家都在
Carol's home, Peggy's home. Everyone's home.
妈妈 快来看啊
Mom! Come quick! Look!
－妈妈 快来 －妈妈 来啊
-Mom, come here! -Mom, come here!
－快看这个 看啊 －快来
-Come see this! Look! -Watch! Come on!
今日早晨在柏林
Francis Gary Powers
弗朗西斯·加里·鲍尔斯
has been released from prison in the Soviet Union
已经从苏联监狱被释放
and turned over to American authorities
并交由美国当局处置
early this morning in Berlin.
总统已经免除了鲁道夫·阿贝尔的刑罚
The President has commuted the sentence of Rudolf Abel.
阿贝尔先生已出境
Mr. Abel has been deported
并在柏林获得释放
and has been released in Berlin.
释放鲍尔斯先生的行动
Efforts to obtain Mr. Powers' release
将于近日实施
had been underway for some time.
在最近的这些活动中
In recent efforts,
美国政府始终
the United States government has had
得到了詹姆斯·B·多诺万先生 一名纽约律师
the cooperation and assistance of Mr. James B. Donovan,
的合作与协助
a New York attorney.
弗雷德里克·L·普莱尔 一名美国学生
Frederic L. Pryor, an American student
始终被东德当局关押
held by East German authorities
从1961年八月
since August of 1961...
我以为爸爸去钓鱼了
I thought Daddy was fishing.
钓鲑鱼
For salmon.
阿贝尔 如今已经消失在了共产主义世界中去了
Abel now has disappeared into the communist world.
鲍尔斯正在接受问询
Powers is here, answering questions.
多诺万已经回到了他的律师事务所
And Donovan has gone back to his law practice.
接下来有请 乔治·芬尼曼
And now, here is George Fenneman,
代表花旗松胶合板协会发言
speaking for the Douglas Fir Plywood Association.